{
	"description": "Kanji for JLPT N2",
	"deck": [
	{ "question": "×", "answers": [ "ばつ" ], "comment": "x-mark (used to indicate an incorrect answer in a test, etc.)\nimpossibility; futility; uselessness" },
	{ "question": "お見舞い", "answers": [ "おみまい" ], "comment": "calling on someone who is ill; enquiry; inquiry" },
	{ "question": "一休み", "answers": [ "ひとやすみ" ], "comment": "(short) rest; breather; break" },
	{ "question": "一定", "answers": [ "いってい" ], "comment": "fixed; settled; constant; definite; uniform; regularized; regularised; defined; standardized; standardised; certain; prescribed" },
	{ "question": "一応", "answers": [ "いちおう" ], "comment": "more or less; though not quite satisfactorily; after a fashion; pretty much; roughly; so far as it goes\ntentatively; for the time being\njust in case\nonce" },
	{ "question": "一斉", "answers": [ "いっせい" ], "comment": "simultaneous; all at once" },
	{ "question": "一旦", "answers": [ "いったん" ], "comment": "once\nfor a short time; briefly; temporarily\none morning" },
	{ "question": "一段と", "answers": [ "いちだんと" ] },
	{ "question": "一流", "answers": [ "いちりゅう" ], "comment": "first-class; top grade; foremost; top-notch; leading\ncharacteristic; peculiar; unique\nschool (e.g. of a performance art)\none flag; one banner; one streamer" },
	{ "question": "一通り", "answers": [ "ひととおり" ], "comment": "(in) general; broad (e.g. knowledge); the basics\nordinary; usual; common\nbriefly; roughly\none method" },
	{ "question": "万歳", "answers": [ "ばんざい" ], "comment": "door-to-door comedic duo\ncrying \"banzai\" (or raising one's hands in the banzai gesture)\nsomething worthy of celebration\ngiving up\nlong time\neternal life (and prosperity)\nbanzai (a celebratory cheer); hurrah (hooray, hurray)" },
	{ "question": "三日月", "answers": [ "みかづき" ], "comment": "new moon; crescent moon" },
	{ "question": "三角", "answers": [ "さんかく" ], "comment": "triangle; triangular" },
	{ "question": "上り", "answers": [ "のぼり" ], "comment": "ascent; climbing; ascending (path); climb\nup-train (e.g. going to Tokyo)\nnorthward (towards Tokyo)" },
	{ "question": "上下", "answers": [ "じょうげ" ], "comment": "top and bottom; up and down; high and low; above and below; upper and lower ends\nupside-down\ntop and bottom; high and low; above and below; upper and lower ends; up and down\ngoing up and down; rising and falling; fluctuating\ngoing and coming back\nupper and lower classes; ruler and ruled; the government and the people\nfirst and second volumes\nsamurai costume; old ceremonial costume\ntop and bottom; up and down; high and low; above and below; upper and lower ends\ntop and bottom; up and down; high and low; above and below; upper and lower ends\nupper and lower classes; ruler and ruled; the government and the people" },
	{ "question": "上旬", "answers": [ "じょうじゅん" ], "comment": "first 10 days of month" },
	{ "question": "上級", "answers": [ "じょうきゅう" ], "comment": "advanced level; high grade; senior" },
	{ "question": "下品", "answers": [ "げひん" ], "comment": "vulgar; indecent; coarse; crude" },
	{ "question": "下旬", "answers": [ "げじゅん" ], "comment": "last third of a month; 21st to the last day of a month" },
	{ "question": "下書き", "answers": [ "したがき" ], "comment": "rough copy; draft; draught" },
	{ "question": "下水", "answers": [ "げすい" ], "comment": "drainage; ditch; gutter; sewerage\nsewage; black water\nwater flowing underneath; one's true feelings\nkanji \"water\" radical at bottom (radical 85)" },
	{ "question": "下町", "answers": [ "したまち" ], "comment": "low-lying part of a city (usu. containing shops, factories, etc.)\nShitamachi (low-lying area of eastern Tokyo near Tokyo Bay, incl. Asakusa, Shitaya, Kanda, Fukugawa, Honjo, Nihonbashi, Kyobashi and surrounds)" },
	{ "question": "下線", "answers": [ "かせん" ], "comment": "underline; underscore" },
	{ "question": "下車", "answers": [ "げしゃ" ], "comment": "alighting (from train, bus, etc.); getting off" },
	{ "question": "下降", "answers": [ "かこう" ], "comment": "descent; fall; drop; decline; downturn; subsidence" },
	{ "question": "下駄", "answers": [ "げた" ], "comment": "geta; Japanese wooden clogs\nturn (in set-type proofing); upside-down character" },
	{ "question": "不潔", "answers": [ "ふけつ" ], "comment": "unclean; dirty; filthy; impure" },
	{ "question": "不規則", "answers": [ "ふきそく" ], "comment": "irregularity; unsteadiness; disorderly" },
	{ "question": "不通", "answers": [ "ふつう" ], "comment": "suspension; interruption; stoppage; tie-up; cessation" },
	{ "question": "不運", "answers": [ "ふうん" ], "comment": "misfortune; bad luck; ill luck; ill fortune; bad break; tough luck; mischance" },
	{ "question": "両側", "answers": [ "りょうがわ" ], "comment": "both sides" },
	{ "question": "並木", "answers": [ "なみき" ], "comment": "roadside tree; row of trees" },
	{ "question": "並行", "answers": [ "へいこう" ], "comment": "(going) side-by-side; abreast\nconcurrent; occurring together; at the same time" },
	{ "question": "中世", "answers": [ "ちゅうせい" ], "comment": "Middle Ages (in Japan esp. the Kamakura and Muromachi periods ); medieval times; mediaeval times" },
	{ "question": "中味", "answers": [ "なかみ" ], "comment": "contents; interior; substance; filling; (sword) blade" },
	{ "question": "中年", "answers": [ "ちゅうねん" ], "comment": "middle-age; middle age; midlife; one's middle years" },
	{ "question": "中性", "answers": [ "ちゅうせい" ], "comment": "neutrality (incl. chemical, electrical, etc.); indifference\nsexlessness; androgyny; androgyne; neuter\nneuter gender" },
	{ "question": "中指", "answers": [ "なかゆび" ], "comment": "middle finger; long finger; second finger; tall finger\nmiddle toe; third toe" },
	{ "question": "中旬", "answers": [ "ちゅうじゅん" ], "comment": "middle of a month; second third of a month; 11th to 20th day of a month" },
	{ "question": "中身", "answers": [ "なかみ" ], "comment": "contents; interior; substance; filling; (sword) blade" },
	{ "question": "中途", "answers": [ "ちゅうと" ], "comment": "in the middle; half-way" },
	{ "question": "中間", "answers": [ "ちゅうかん" ], "comment": "middle; midway; interim\nsamurai's attendant; footman" },
	{ "question": "主役", "answers": [ "しゅやく" ], "comment": "leading part; leading actor; leading actress" },
	{ "question": "主語", "answers": [ "しゅご" ], "comment": "subject" },
	{ "question": "丼", "answers": [ "どんぶり" ], "comment": "porcelain bowl\nbowl of rice with food on top" },
	{ "question": "乗換", "answers": [ "のりかえ" ], "comment": "transfer (trains, buses, etc.); connection; connexion\nswitching (stock)\nchromosomal crossover; crossing over" },
	{ "question": "乗車", "answers": [ "じょうしゃ" ], "comment": "taking a train, bus, etc.; entraining" },
	{ "question": "乱暴", "answers": [ "らんぼう" ], "comment": "rude; violent; rough; lawless; unreasonable; reckless" },
	{ "question": "乾かす", "answers": [ "かわかす" ], "comment": "to dry (clothes, etc.); to desiccate" },
	{ "question": "乾く", "answers": [ "かわく" ], "comment": "to get dry" },
	{ "question": "乾杯", "answers": [ "かんぱい" ], "comment": "toast; drink (in celebration or in honor of something)\ndrinking one's glass dry\ncheers" },
	{ "question": "乾燥", "answers": [ "かんそう" ], "comment": "dryness; aridity; insipidity; dehydration; desiccation" },
	{ "question": "乾電池", "answers": [ "かんでんち" ], "comment": "dry cell; battery" },
	{ "question": "予備", "answers": [ "よび" ], "comment": "preparation; preliminaries; reserve; spare" },
	{ "question": "争う", "answers": [ "あらそう" ], "comment": "to compete; to contest; to contend\nto quarrel; to argue; to dispute; to be at variance; to oppose\n(usu. in negative form) to deny (e.g. evidence)\nto go against; to fight against; to oppose; to resist; to deny" },
	{ "question": "五十音", "answers": [ "ごじゅうおん" ], "comment": "the Japanese syllabary" },
	{ "question": "井戸", "answers": [ "いど" ], "comment": "water well" },
	{ "question": "亡くす", "answers": [ "なくす" ], "comment": "to lose something\nto get rid of\nto lose someone (wife, child, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "交ざる", "answers": [ "まざる" ], "comment": "to be mixed; to be blended with; to associate with; to mingle with; to join" },
	{ "question": "交じる", "answers": [ "まじる" ], "comment": "to be mixed; to be blended with; to associate with; to mingle with; to interest; to join" },
	{ "question": "交ぜる", "answers": [ "まぜる" ], "comment": "to mix; to stir; to blend" },
	{ "question": "交差", "answers": [ "こうさ" ], "comment": "crossing; intersection\n(genetic) crossing over" },
	{ "question": "交替", "answers": [ "こうたい" ], "comment": "alternation; change; relief; relay; shift; substitution (sports, etc.); taking turns" },
	{ "question": "交流", "answers": [ "こうりゅう" ], "comment": "(cultural) exchange; interchange; interaction; (inter-) mingling; (social, etc.) networking; intercourse\nalternating current; AC" },
	{ "question": "交通機関", "answers": [ "こうつうきかん" ], "comment": "transportation facilities" },
	{ "question": "人命", "answers": [ "じんめい" ], "comment": "(human) life" },
	{ "question": "人差指", "answers": [ "ひとさしゆび" ], "comment": "index finger; forefinger" },
	{ "question": "人文科学", "answers": [ "じんぶんかがく" ], "comment": "humanities; social sciences; liberal arts" },
	{ "question": "人通り", "answers": [ "ひとどおり" ], "comment": "pedestrian traffic" },
	{ "question": "人造", "answers": [ "じんぞう" ], "comment": "man-made; synthetic; artificial" },
	{ "question": "仕上がる", "answers": [ "しあがる" ], "comment": "to be finished; to be completed; to be done" },
	{ "question": "付合う", "answers": [ "つきあう" ], "comment": "to associate with; to keep company with; to go out with; to go steady with; to get on with\nto go along with; to follow someone's lead; to accompany someone; to compromise" },
	{ "question": "付近", "answers": [ "ふきん" ], "comment": "neighbourhood; neighborhood; vicinity; environs\napproaching" },
	{ "question": "代える", "answers": [ "かえる" ], "comment": "to replace\nto exchange; to interchange\nto substitute" },
	{ "question": "代る", "answers": [ "かわる" ], "comment": "to succeed; to relieve; to replace\nto take the place of; to substitute for; to take over for; to represent\nto be exchanged; to change (places with); to switch" },
	{ "question": "代名詞", "answers": [ "だいめいし" ], "comment": "pronoun\nsynonym; classic example; pattern; byword; representative" },
	{ "question": "以後", "answers": [ "いご" ], "comment": "after this; from now on; hereafter\nthereafter; since (verb) (after -te form of verb); after (time); since (then)" },
	{ "question": "以降", "answers": [ "いこう" ], "comment": "on and after; as from; hereafter; thereafter; since" },
	{ "question": "仮名", "answers": [ "かな" ], "comment": "alias; pseudonym; pen name; nom de plume\nkana; Japanese syllabary (i.e. hiragana, katakana)" },
	{ "question": "仮名遣い", "answers": [ "かなづかい" ], "comment": "kana orthography; syllabary spelling" },
	{ "question": "仮定", "answers": [ "かてい" ], "comment": "assumption; supposition; hypothesis" },
	{ "question": "仲直り", "answers": [ "なかなおり" ], "comment": "reconciliation; make peace with" },
	{ "question": "仲良し", "answers": [ "なかよし" ], "comment": "intimate friend; close friend; bosom buddy; chum" },
	{ "question": "休息", "answers": [ "きゅうそく" ], "comment": "rest; relief; relaxation" },
	{ "question": "休業", "answers": [ "きゅうぎょう" ], "comment": "closed (e.g. store); business suspended; shutdown; holiday" },
	{ "question": "休講", "answers": [ "きゅうこう" ], "comment": "lecture cancellation; cancelling (lecture, class, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "休養", "answers": [ "きゅうよう" ], "comment": "rest; break; recreation" },
	{ "question": "会館", "answers": [ "かいかん" ], "comment": "meeting hall; assembly hall" },
	{ "question": "伝わる", "answers": [ "つたわる" ], "comment": "to be handed down; to be introduced; to be transmitted; to be circulated; to go along; to walk along" },
	{ "question": "伝染", "answers": [ "でんせん" ], "comment": "contagion; infection" },
	{ "question": "伝記", "answers": [ "でんき" ], "comment": "biography; life story" },
	{ "question": "伯母さん", "answers": [ "おばさん" ], "comment": "aunt" },
	{ "question": "伯父さん", "answers": [ "おじさん" ], "comment": "uncle\nold man; mister (vocative)\nmanybar goatfish (Parupeneus multifasciatus)" },
	{ "question": "但し", "answers": [ "ただし" ], "comment": "but; however; provided that" },
	{ "question": "低下", "answers": [ "ていか" ], "comment": "fall; decline; lowering; deterioration; degradation" },
	{ "question": "住まい", "answers": [ "すまい" ], "comment": "dwelling; house; residence; address" },
	{ "question": "住居", "answers": [ "じゅうきょ" ], "comment": "dwelling; house; residence; address" },
	{ "question": "体制", "answers": [ "たいせい" ], "comment": "order; system; structure; set-up; organization; organisation" },
	{ "question": "体操", "answers": [ "たいそう" ], "comment": "gymnastics; physical exercises; calisthenics" },
	{ "question": "体積", "answers": [ "たいせき" ], "comment": "capacity; volume" },
	{ "question": "体系", "answers": [ "たいけい" ], "comment": "system; organization; organisation; architecture" },
	{ "question": "何々", "answers": [ "なになに" ], "comment": "such and such (when being vague, placeholder, etc.); this and that\nWhat?; What is the matter?; What are the items?" },
	{ "question": "何分", "answers": [ "なにぶん" ], "comment": "some; any; (a) little; of some kind; of some sort\nplease\nanyway; anyhow; at any rate; after all\nwhat minute?; how many minutes?" },
	{ "question": "余る", "answers": [ "あまる" ], "comment": "to remain; to be left over; to be in excess; to be too many" },
	{ "question": "余所", "answers": [ "よそ" ], "comment": "another place; somewhere else; strange parts\noutside (one's family or group); those people\nunrelated matter" },
	{ "question": "余計", "answers": [ "よけい" ], "comment": "too many; too much; excessive; superfluous; superabundant; extra; spare; surplus\nunnecessary; needless; uncalled-for; otiose\nabundantly; excessively; needlessly; all the more" },
	{ "question": "作成", "answers": [ "さくせい" ], "comment": "drawing up (e.g. legal document, contract, will, etc.); preparing; writing; framing; making; producing; creating; creation" },
	{ "question": "作者", "answers": [ "さくしゃ" ], "comment": "author; authoress; writer; composer; artist" },
	{ "question": "作製", "answers": [ "さくせい" ], "comment": "manufacture" },
	{ "question": "例える", "answers": [ "たとえる" ], "comment": "to compare; to liken; to speak figuratively; to illustrate; to use a simile" },
	{ "question": "例外", "answers": [ "れいがい" ], "comment": "exception" },
	{ "question": "侵入", "answers": [ "しんにゅう" ], "comment": "invasion; incursion; raid; aggression; intrusion; trespass; penetration" },
	{ "question": "便所", "answers": [ "べんじょ" ], "comment": "toilet; lavatory; rest room; latrine; comfort station\nhairdresser's room in the residence of the shogun or a noble" },
	{ "question": "便箋", "answers": [ "びんせん" ], "comment": "writing paper; stationery" },
	{ "question": "係わる", "answers": [ "かかわる" ], "comment": "to be affected; to be influenced\nto be concerned with; to have to do with\nto stick to (opinions)" },
	{ "question": "保健", "answers": [ "ほけん" ], "comment": "health preservation; hygiene; sanitation" },
	{ "question": "信ずる", "answers": [ "しんずる" ], "comment": "to believe; to believe in; to place trust in; to confide in; to have faith in" },
	{ "question": "修繕", "answers": [ "しゅうぜん" ], "comment": "repair; mending" },
	{ "question": "俳句", "answers": [ "はいく" ], "comment": "haiku; 17-mora poem, usu. in 3 lines of 5, 7 and 5 morae" },
	{ "question": "倉庫", "answers": [ "そうこ" ], "comment": "storehouse; warehouse; godown" },
	{ "question": "個体", "answers": [ "こたい" ], "comment": "individual; specimen" },
	{ "question": "個所", "answers": [ "かしょ" ], "comment": "passage; place; point; part" },
	{ "question": "倣う", "answers": [ "ならう" ], "comment": "to imitate; to follow; to emulate" },
	{ "question": "偉い", "answers": [ "えらい" ], "comment": "great; excellent; admirable; remarkable; distinguished; important; celebrated; famous; eminent\nawful; terrible" },
	{ "question": "停止", "answers": [ "ていし" ], "comment": "suspension; interruption; stoppage; ban; standstill; halt; hang-up; deadlock; stalemate; abeyance\nsuspension of music, dance, etc. as a sign of mourning for a prominent person" },
	{ "question": "停車", "answers": [ "ていしゃ" ], "comment": "stopping (e.g. train)" },
	{ "question": "停電", "answers": [ "ていでん" ], "comment": "power outage; electricity outage; blackout; failure of electricity supply" },
	{ "question": "偶数", "answers": [ "ぐうすう" ], "comment": "even number" },
	{ "question": "傑作", "answers": [ "けっさく" ], "comment": "masterpiece; best work\namusing blunder; funny mistake; boner" },
	{ "question": "催し", "answers": [ "もよおし" ], "comment": "event; festivities; function; social gathering; auspices; opening; holding (a meeting)" },
	{ "question": "催促", "answers": [ "さいそく" ], "comment": "pressing; demanding; urging; demand; request; claim" },
	{ "question": "傾く", "answers": [ "かたむく" ], "comment": "to incline toward; to slant; to lurch; to heel over; to be disposed to; to trend toward; to be prone to\nto go down (sun); to wane; to sink; to decline\nto lean (esp. of a ripe ear of rice); to incline; to slant; to tilt\nto behave oddly; to attire oneself strangely\nto perform kabuki" },
	{ "question": "傾らか", "answers": [ "なだらか" ], "comment": "gently sloping; gentle; easy\nsmooth" },
	{ "question": "儀式", "answers": [ "ぎしき" ], "comment": "ceremony; rite; ritual; service" },
	{ "question": "元々", "answers": [ "もともと" ], "comment": "originally; by nature; from the start" },
	{ "question": "先々月", "answers": [ "せんせんげつ" ], "comment": "month before last" },
	{ "question": "先々週", "answers": [ "せんせんしゅう" ], "comment": "week before last" },
	{ "question": "先祖", "answers": [ "せんぞ" ], "comment": "ancestor" },
	{ "question": "先程", "answers": [ "さきほど" ], "comment": "some time ago; not long ago; just now" },
	{ "question": "先端", "answers": [ "せんたん" ], "comment": "pointed end; tip; fine point; spearhead; cusp; vanguard; advanced; leading edge; apex (of a curve)" },
	{ "question": "先頭", "answers": [ "せんとう" ], "comment": "head; lead; vanguard; first" },
	{ "question": "光線", "answers": [ "こうせん" ], "comment": "beam; light ray" },
	{ "question": "免税", "answers": [ "めんぜい" ], "comment": "tax exemption; duty exemption" },
	{ "question": "児童", "answers": [ "じどう" ], "comment": "children; juvenile" },
	{ "question": "入れ物", "answers": [ "いれもの" ], "comment": "container; case; receptacle\n(euph. for) coffin; casket" },
	{ "question": "入社", "answers": [ "にゅうしゃ" ], "comment": "joining a company; getting a job with a company; entering a company" },
	{ "question": "全般", "answers": [ "ぜんぱん" ], "comment": "(the) whole; universal; wholly; general; as a whole" },
	{ "question": "全身", "answers": [ "ぜんしん" ], "comment": "whole (body); full-length (e.g. portrait)\nsystemic" },
	{ "question": "全集", "answers": [ "ぜんしゅう" ], "comment": "complete works" },
	{ "question": "公共", "answers": [ "こうきょう" ], "comment": "public; community; public service; society; communal" },
	{ "question": "公務", "answers": [ "こうむ" ], "comment": "official business; public business" },
	{ "question": "公害", "answers": [ "こうがい" ], "comment": "pollution; public nuisance; contamination" },
	{ "question": "公式", "answers": [ "こうしき" ], "comment": "formal; official\nformula (e.g. mathematical)" },
	{ "question": "公正", "answers": [ "こうせい" ], "comment": "justice; fairness; impartiality" },
	{ "question": "公衆", "answers": [ "こうしゅう" ], "comment": "the public; general public" },
	{ "question": "公表", "answers": [ "こうひょう" ], "comment": "official announcement; proclamation" },
	{ "question": "兵隊", "answers": [ "へいたい" ], "comment": "soldier; sailor" },
	{ "question": "兼ねる", "answers": [ "かねる" ], "comment": "to be unable to; to find difficult (unpleasant, awkward, painful) to do\nto serve two or more functions or roles simultaneously; to contain (or combine) two or more features\nto work in two or more jobs simultaneously (positions, etc.); to do alongside\nto hesitate to do something (out of consideration for others)\nto think of the future (as well as the present)" },
	{ "question": "内科", "answers": [ "ないか" ], "comment": "internal medicine, i.e. treatment by medical procedures rather than surgical procedures\ndepartment of internal medicine (hospital, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "内線", "answers": [ "ないせん" ], "comment": "phone extension; indoor wiring; inner line" },
	{ "question": "円い", "answers": [ "まるい" ], "comment": "round; circular; spherical\nharmonious; calm" },
	{ "question": "円周", "answers": [ "えんしゅう" ], "comment": "circumference" },
	{ "question": "再三", "answers": [ "さいさん" ], "comment": "again and again; repeatedly" },
	{ "question": "再来年", "answers": [ "さらいねん" ], "comment": "year after next" },
	{ "question": "再来月", "answers": [ "さらいげつ" ], "comment": "month after next" },
	{ "question": "再来週", "answers": [ "さらいしゅう" ], "comment": "week after next" },
	{ "question": "写る", "answers": [ "うつる" ], "comment": "to be photographed; to be projected" },
	{ "question": "写生", "answers": [ "しゃせい" ], "comment": "sketching; drawing from nature; portrayal; description" },
	{ "question": "冠", "answers": [ "かんむり" ], "comment": "cap (esp. a traditional cap worn with sokutai or ikan clothing); crown; diadem; coronet\ntop kanji radical\nfirst verse of a haikai, etc.\nbest; peerless; first\nname; title; named sponsorship of a program, event, team, etc.\norder; rank" },
	{ "question": "冷ます", "answers": [ "さます" ], "comment": "to cool (e.g. from a high temperature to room temperature); to let cool\nto dampen; to throw a damper on; to spoil" },
	{ "question": "冷める", "answers": [ "さめる" ], "comment": "to become cool (e.g. from a high temperature to room temperature); to come down (fever)\nto cool down (interest); to abate; to subside; to dampen" },
	{ "question": "冷やす", "answers": [ "ひやす" ], "comment": "to cool (from room temperature); to chill; to refrigerate\nto calm down; to cool off; to regain one's composure; to relax\nto be frightened (at); to be scared (of)" },
	{ "question": "冷凍", "answers": [ "れいとう" ], "comment": "freezing; cold storage; refrigeration" },
	{ "question": "凍える", "answers": [ "こごえる" ], "comment": "to freeze (of one's body); to be frozen; to become numb (with cold); to be chilled" },
	{ "question": "凸凹", "answers": [ "でこぼこ" ], "comment": "unevenness; roughness; ruggedness\ninequality" },
	{ "question": "凹む", "answers": [ "へこむ" ], "comment": "to be dented; to be indented; to yield to; to give; to sink; to collapse; to cave in\nto be overwhelmed; to feel down; to be forced to yield; to be daunted; to be snubbed\nto cave in; to become depressed; to sink" },
	{ "question": "出入り", "answers": [ "でいり" ], "comment": "in and out; coming and going; free association; income and expenditure; debits and credit" },
	{ "question": "出入口", "answers": [ "でいりぐち" ], "comment": "exit and entrance" },
	{ "question": "出勤", "answers": [ "しゅっきん" ], "comment": "attendance (at work); being at work; presence (in the office); going to work; reporting for work" },
	{ "question": "出合い", "answers": [ "であい" ], "comment": "meeting; rendezvous; encounter\nconfluence" },
	{ "question": "出張", "answers": [ "しゅっちょう" ], "comment": "official tour; business trip" },
	{ "question": "出掛ける", "answers": [ "でかける" ], "comment": "to go out (e.g. on an excursion or outing); to leave; to depart; to start; to set out\nto be about to leave; to be just going out" },
	{ "question": "出来上がり", "answers": [ "できあがり" ], "comment": "finish; completion; ready; made for; cut out" },
	{ "question": "出来上がる", "answers": [ "できあがる" ], "comment": "to be completed; to be finished; to be ready (e.g. to serve or eat)\nto be very drunk" },
	{ "question": "出迎え", "answers": [ "でむかえ" ], "comment": "meeting; reception" },
	{ "question": "出迎える", "answers": [ "でむかえる" ], "comment": "to meet; to greet" },
	{ "question": "分かれる", "answers": [ "わかれる" ], "comment": "to branch; to fork; to diverge\nto separate; to split; to divide\nto disperse; to scatter" },
	{ "question": "分る", "answers": [ "わかる" ], "comment": "to understand; to comprehend; to grasp; to see; to get; to follow\nto become clear; to be known; to be discovered; to be realized; to be realised; to be found out" },
	{ "question": "分布", "answers": [ "ぶんぷ" ], "comment": "distribution; allocation" },
	{ "question": "分数", "answers": [ "ぶんすう" ], "comment": "fraction" },
	{ "question": "分解", "answers": [ "ぶんかい" ], "comment": "disassembly; dismantling; disaggregating; analysis; disintegrating; decomposing; degrading\nfactorization\ndecomposition; resolution\ndeblocking" },
	{ "question": "分量", "answers": [ "ぶんりょう" ], "comment": "amount; quantity" },
	{ "question": "分類", "answers": [ "ぶんるい" ], "comment": "classification; categorization; sorting" },
	{ "question": "列島", "answers": [ "れっとう" ], "comment": "archipelago; chain of islands" },
	{ "question": "初めに", "answers": [ "はじめに" ], "comment": "first; firstly; first of all; to begin with; in the beginning; at the beginning\nIntroduction; Preface" },
	{ "question": "初旬", "answers": [ "しょじゅん" ], "comment": "first 10 days of the month" },
	{ "question": "初級", "answers": [ "しょきゅう" ], "comment": "elementary level" },
	{ "question": "判事", "answers": [ "はんじ" ], "comment": "judge; judiciary" },
	{ "question": "判子", "answers": [ "はんこ" ], "comment": "seal (used for signature)" },
	{ "question": "別々", "answers": [ "べつべつ" ], "comment": "separately; individually" },
	{ "question": "別荘", "answers": [ "べっそう" ], "comment": "holiday house; villa" },
	{ "question": "利害", "answers": [ "りがい" ], "comment": "advantages and disadvantages; interest" },
	{ "question": "制作", "answers": [ "せいさく" ], "comment": "work (film, book)\nproduction; creation; turning (something) out; development" },
	{ "question": "刷る", "answers": [ "する" ], "comment": "to print\nto color or pattern fabric using a wooden mold" },
	{ "question": "刺さる", "answers": [ "ささる" ], "comment": "to stick into (something with a sharp point); to prick; to pierce; to get stuck (in); to lodge (in)" },
	{ "question": "刺す", "answers": [ "さす" ], "comment": "to pierce; to stab; to prick; to stick; to thrust\nto sting; to bite\nto sew; to stitch; to embroider\nto pole (a boat)\nto catch (with a limed pole)\nto put (a runner) out; to pick off" },
	{ "question": "刺身", "answers": [ "さしみ" ], "comment": "sashimi (raw sliced fish, shellfish or crustaceans)" },
	{ "question": "刻む", "answers": [ "きざむ" ], "comment": "to mince; to cut fine; to chop up; to hash; to shred\nto carve; to engrave; to chisel; to notch\nto tick away (time); to beat out (e.g. rhythm); to record the passing moments\nto etch (into one's mind); to remember distinctly\nto have tattooed\nto torment" },
	{ "question": "削る", "answers": [ "けずる" ], "comment": "to shave (wood or leather); to sharpen; to plane; to whittle; to pare; to scrape off\nto shave off (e.g. a budget, expenses, a salary, etc.); to curtail; to cut down\nto cross out; to reduce; to curtail; to remove; to erase; to delete\nto shave off (esp. concrete)\nto take a percentage; to take a cut" },
	{ "question": "削除", "answers": [ "さくじょ" ], "comment": "deletion; elimination; erasure; striking out" },
	{ "question": "前後", "answers": [ "ぜんご" ], "comment": "front and rear; front and back; before and behind; back and forth\nbefore and after\norder; context\nconsequences\ninversion; reversion; getting out of order\nco-occurring\naround; about; approximately; nearly\nfront and rear; front and back; before and behind" },
	{ "question": "剥く", "answers": [ "むく" ], "comment": "to peel; to skin; to pare; to hull; to bare (e.g. fangs); to open wide (e.g. eyes)" },
	{ "question": "剥す", "answers": [ "はがす" ], "comment": "to tear off; to peel off; to rip off; to strip off; to skin; to flay; to disrobe; to deprive of; to detach; to disconnect" },
	{ "question": "副詞", "answers": [ "ふくし" ], "comment": "adverb" },
	{ "question": "割と", "answers": [ "わりと" ], "comment": "relatively; comparatively" },
	{ "question": "割れる", "answers": [ "われる" ], "comment": "to break; to be smashed\nto split; to crack; to fissure; to be torn\nto be divided; to cleave\nto come to light; to be identified; to be established; to become clear" },
	{ "question": "割合", "answers": [ "わりあい" ], "comment": "rate; ratio; percentage; proportion\ncomparatively\ncontrary to expectations" },
	{ "question": "割引", "answers": [ "わりびき" ], "comment": "discount; reduction; rebate; (after a number) tenths discounted; tenths reduced" },
	{ "question": "割算", "answers": [ "わりざん" ], "comment": "division" },
	{ "question": "創作", "answers": [ "そうさく" ], "comment": "production; literary creation; work" },
	{ "question": "力強い", "answers": [ "ちからづよい" ], "comment": "powerful; strong; forceful; vigorous\nreassuring; encouraging" },
	{ "question": "功績", "answers": [ "こうせき" ], "comment": "achievements; merit; meritorious service; meritorious deed" },
	{ "question": "加熱", "answers": [ "かねつ" ], "comment": "heating; application of heat" },
	{ "question": "加速", "answers": [ "かそく" ], "comment": "acceleration; speeding up" },
	{ "question": "加速度", "answers": [ "かそくど" ], "comment": "acceleration" },
	{ "question": "助かる", "answers": [ "たすかる" ], "comment": "to be saved; to be rescued; to survive\nto escape harm; to be spared damage\nto be helped; to be saved trouble" },
	{ "question": "助教授", "answers": [ "じょきょうじゅ" ], "comment": "assistant professor; associate professor" },
	{ "question": "努める", "answers": [ "つとめる" ], "comment": "to endeavor (endeavour); to try; to strive; to make an effort; to exert oneself; to be diligent; to be committed (to doing something)" },
	{ "question": "効力", "answers": [ "こうりょく" ], "comment": "effect; efficacy; validity; potency" },
	{ "question": "勇ましい", "answers": [ "いさましい" ], "comment": "brave; valiant; gallant; courageous\nstirring; vigorous; rousing" },
	{ "question": "動作", "answers": [ "どうさ" ], "comment": "action; movements; motions; bearing; behaviour; behavior; execution; actuation; operation; manners" },
	{ "question": "勘違い", "answers": [ "かんちがい" ], "comment": "misunderstanding; wrong guess" },
	{ "question": "務める", "answers": [ "つとめる" ], "comment": "to work (for); to be employed (at); to serve (in)\nto serve (as); to act (as); to fill (the position of); to play the role (of)\nto conduct a religious service" },
	{ "question": "勝敗", "answers": [ "しょうはい" ], "comment": "victory or defeat; issue (of battle); outcome" },
	{ "question": "勝負", "answers": [ "しょうぶ" ], "comment": "victory or defeat; match; contest; game; bout" },
	{ "question": "募集", "answers": [ "ぼしゅう" ], "comment": "recruiting; selection; taking applications\nraising; collection; subscription; soliciting (e.g. donations)\nflotation (shares, loans, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "匂う", "answers": [ "におう" ], "comment": "to be fragrant; to smell (good)\nto stink; to smell (bad)\nto glow; to be bright\nto smack of; to show hints of" },
	{ "question": "包丁", "answers": [ "ほうちょう" ], "comment": "kitchen knife; carving knife\ncooking; food" },
	{ "question": "包帯", "answers": [ "ほうたい" ], "comment": "bandage; dressing" },
	{ "question": "包装", "answers": [ "ほうそう" ], "comment": "packing; wrapping" },
	{ "question": "北極", "answers": [ "ほっきょく" ], "comment": "North Pole\nthe Arctic" },
	{ "question": "区分", "answers": [ "くぶん" ], "comment": "division; section; demarcation; partition; segmentation; subdivision; (traffic) lane; compartment; classification; sorting" },
	{ "question": "区切る", "answers": [ "くぎる" ], "comment": "to demarcate; to delimit; to divide (an area); to mark off; to cut off\nto punctuate; to put an end to (e.g. a sentence); to insert pauses or breaks (e.g. when reading aloud)" },
	{ "question": "区域", "answers": [ "くいき" ], "comment": "limits; boundary; domain; zone; sphere; territory\narea (e.g. in programming languages)" },
	{ "question": "半島", "answers": [ "はんとう" ], "comment": "peninsula" },
	{ "question": "半径", "answers": [ "はんけい" ], "comment": "radius" },
	{ "question": "南北", "answers": [ "なんぼく" ], "comment": "north and south; north to south\nSouth Korea and North Korea" },
	{ "question": "南極", "answers": [ "なんきょく" ], "comment": "South Pole\nthe Antarctic; Antarctica" },
	{ "question": "南米", "answers": [ "なんべい" ], "comment": "South America" },
	{ "question": "単数", "answers": [ "たんすう" ], "comment": "singular number" },
	{ "question": "占う", "answers": [ "うらなう" ], "comment": "to tell someone's fortune; to forecast; to predict; to divine" },
	{ "question": "危うい", "answers": [ "あやうい" ], "comment": "dangerous; risky; hazardous; perilous; precarious\nin danger; in jeopardy; critical; grave; at risk\nuncertain; unreliable; insecure; unsteady; doubtful\nclose (i.e. a close call); narrow" },
	{ "question": "卸す", "answers": [ "おろす" ], "comment": "to sell wholesale\nto grate (e.g. vegetables)\nto cut up fish" },
	{ "question": "厚かましい", "answers": [ "あつかましい" ], "comment": "impudent; shameless; brazen" },
	{ "question": "原始", "answers": [ "げんし" ], "comment": "origin; primeval" },
	{ "question": "原料", "answers": [ "げんりょう" ], "comment": "raw materials" },
	{ "question": "原理", "answers": [ "げんり" ], "comment": "principle; theory; fundamental truth" },
	{ "question": "原産", "answers": [ "げんさん" ], "comment": "place of origin; habitat" },
	{ "question": "原稿", "answers": [ "げんこう" ], "comment": "manuscript; copy" },
	{ "question": "厳重", "answers": [ "げんじゅう" ], "comment": "strict; rigour; rigor; severe; firm; strong; secure" },
	{ "question": "又は", "answers": [ "または" ], "comment": "or; otherwise" },
	{ "question": "友好", "answers": [ "ゆうこう" ], "comment": "friendship" },
	{ "question": "反る", "answers": [ "かえる" ], "comment": "to warp; to be warped; to curve; to be curved; to be arched; to bend; to be bent\nto bend backward (body or body part, e.g. fingers)\nto return; to come back; to go back\nto turn over\n(after the -masu stem of a verb) (to become) extremely; (to become) completely" },
	{ "question": "反映", "answers": [ "はんえい" ], "comment": "reflection (light, image, situation, attitude, etc.); reflecting\ninfluence; application (e.g. of an update)" },
	{ "question": "反省", "answers": [ "はんせい" ], "comment": "reflection; reconsideration; introspection; meditation; contemplation\nregret; repentance; remorse; being sorry" },
	{ "question": "叔母さん", "answers": [ "おばさん" ], "comment": "aunt" },
	{ "question": "叔父さん", "answers": [ "おじさん" ], "comment": "uncle\nold man; mister (vocative)\nmanybar goatfish (Parupeneus multifasciatus)" },
	{ "question": "取り入れる", "answers": [ "とりいれる" ], "comment": "to harvest; to reap\nto take in; to gather in\nto adopt (e.g. idea); to accept (e.g. advice); to introduce; to borrow (e.g. word)" },
	{ "question": "取り出す", "answers": [ "とりだす" ], "comment": "to take out; to produce; to pick out\nto fetch; to retrieve" },
	{ "question": "取り消す", "answers": [ "とりけす" ], "comment": "to cancel; to withdraw; to retract; to take back (words, etc.); to revoke" },
	{ "question": "受け持つ", "answers": [ "うけもつ" ], "comment": "to take (be in) charge of" },
	{ "question": "受取", "answers": [ "うけとり" ], "comment": "receipt" },
	{ "question": "受話器", "answers": [ "じゅわき" ], "comment": "(telephone) receiver" },
	{ "question": "受験", "answers": [ "じゅけん" ], "comment": "taking an examination (esp. school and university entrance)" },
	{ "question": "口実", "answers": [ "こうじつ" ], "comment": "excuse; pretext" },
	{ "question": "口紅", "answers": [ "くちべに" ], "comment": "lipstick" },
	{ "question": "古典", "answers": [ "こてん" ], "comment": "old book; classics; classic" },
	{ "question": "句読点", "answers": [ "くとうてん" ], "comment": "punctuation mark; punctuation marks" },
	{ "question": "可決", "answers": [ "かけつ" ], "comment": "approval; adoption (e.g. motion, bill); passage" },
	{ "question": "司会", "answers": [ "しかい" ], "comment": "leading a meeting; presiding over a meeting; officiating at a ceremony; chairmanship\nchairman; presenter; host; moderator; master of ceremonies" },
	{ "question": "各々", "answers": [ "おのおの" ], "comment": "each\nyou (plural)" },
	{ "question": "各地", "answers": [ "かくち" ], "comment": "every place; various places" },
	{ "question": "各自", "answers": [ "かくじ" ], "comment": "each (person); everyone; individual; respective" },
	{ "question": "合同", "answers": [ "ごうどう" ], "comment": "combination; union; incorporation; amalgamation; fusion\ncongruence" },
	{ "question": "合流", "answers": [ "ごうりゅう" ], "comment": "confluence (of rivers); merge (of traffic); conflux; junction; joining\nunion (e.g. of forces); linking up; merging; coming together" },
	{ "question": "合理", "answers": [ "ごうり" ], "comment": "rationality" },
	{ "question": "同格", "answers": [ "どうかく" ], "comment": "the same rank; equality\napposition" },
	{ "question": "名作", "answers": [ "めいさく" ], "comment": "masterpiece" },
	{ "question": "名刺", "answers": [ "めいし" ], "comment": "business card" },
	{ "question": "名字", "answers": [ "みょうじ" ], "comment": "surname; family name" },
	{ "question": "名所", "answers": [ "めいしょ" ], "comment": "famous place\nname of a part (of an instrument, etc.)\nname and address" },
	{ "question": "名物", "answers": [ "めいぶつ" ], "comment": "famous product; special product; speciality; specialty" },
	{ "question": "名詞", "answers": [ "めいし" ], "comment": "noun" },
	{ "question": "吐き気", "answers": [ "はきけ" ], "comment": "nausea; sickness in the stomach" },
	{ "question": "向う", "answers": [ "むかう" ], "comment": "to face\nto go towards; to head towards" },
	{ "question": "含める", "answers": [ "ふくめる" ], "comment": "to include (in a group or scope)\nto instruct; to make one understand\nto include (a nuance); to put in (an implication)\nto put in (someone's) mouth\nto permeate with flavor" },
	{ "question": "吹雪", "answers": [ "ふぶき" ], "comment": "snow storm; blizzard" },
	{ "question": "周辺", "answers": [ "しゅうへん" ], "comment": "circumference; outskirts; environs; around; in the area of; in the vicinity of\n(computer) peripheral" },
	{ "question": "味わう", "answers": [ "あじわう" ], "comment": "to taste; to savor; to savour; to relish\nto appreciate; to enjoy; to relish; to digest\nto taste; to experience; to undergo; to endure" },
	{ "question": "呼び出す", "answers": [ "よびだす" ], "comment": "to summon; to call (e.g. phone); to convene; to decoy; to lure\nto invoke (e.g. subroutine); to call; to open (e.g. a file)" },
	{ "question": "呼び掛ける", "answers": [ "よびかける" ], "comment": "to call out to; to hail; to address\nto appeal" },
	{ "question": "命ずる", "answers": [ "めいずる" ], "comment": "to command; to appoint" },
	{ "question": "和服", "answers": [ "わふく" ], "comment": "Japanese clothes" },
	{ "question": "和英", "answers": [ "わえい" ], "comment": "Japanese-English" },
	{ "question": "唇", "answers": [ "くちびる" ], "comment": "lips" },
	{ "question": "商店", "answers": [ "しょうてん" ], "comment": "shop; small store; business; firm" },
	{ "question": "商業", "answers": [ "しょうぎょう" ], "comment": "commerce; trade; business" },
	{ "question": "商社", "answers": [ "しょうしゃ" ], "comment": "trading company; firm" },
	{ "question": "問い合わせ", "answers": [ "といあわせ" ], "comment": "enquiry; inquiry; query; interrogation; ENQ" },
	{ "question": "問答", "answers": [ "もんどう" ], "comment": "questions and answers; dialogue" },
	{ "question": "嗅ぐ", "answers": [ "かぐ" ], "comment": "to sniff; to smell" },
	{ "question": "器具", "answers": [ "きぐ" ], "comment": "utensil; apparatus; implement; device; gadget" },
	{ "question": "器械", "answers": [ "きかい" ], "comment": "machine; mechanism\ninstrument; appliance; apparatus" },
	{ "question": "噴水", "answers": [ "ふんすい" ], "comment": "water fountain" },
	{ "question": "噴火", "answers": [ "ふんか" ], "comment": "eruption" },
	{ "question": "四つ角", "answers": [ "よつかど" ], "comment": "four corners; crossroads" },
	{ "question": "四季", "answers": [ "しき" ], "comment": "four seasons" },
	{ "question": "四捨五入", "answers": [ "ししゃごにゅう" ], "comment": "rounding (fractions); rounding half up" },
	{ "question": "四角", "answers": [ "しかく" ], "comment": "square" },
	{ "question": "四角い", "answers": [ "しかくい" ], "comment": "square; rectangular" },
	{ "question": "回り道", "answers": [ "まわりみち" ], "comment": "detour; diversion" },
	{ "question": "回数", "answers": [ "かいすう" ], "comment": "number of times; frequency; count" },
	{ "question": "回数券", "answers": [ "かいすうけん" ], "comment": "book of tickets" },
	{ "question": "回答", "answers": [ "かいとう" ], "comment": "reply; answer" },
	{ "question": "回転", "answers": [ "かいてん" ], "comment": "rotation (usu. around something); revolution; turning" },
	{ "question": "因る", "answers": [ "よる" ], "comment": "to be due to; to be caused by\nto depend on; to turn on\nto be based on; to come from\nto be based at (a location, an organization); to be headquartered at" },
	{ "question": "団地", "answers": [ "だんち" ], "comment": "multi-unit apartments; apartment complex" },
	{ "question": "図形", "answers": [ "ずけい" ], "comment": "figure; shape; graphic" },
	{ "question": "図表", "answers": [ "ずひょう" ], "comment": "chart; diagram; graph; figure" },
	{ "question": "図鑑", "answers": [ "ずかん" ], "comment": "pictorial book; picture book; illustrated reference book; identification manual; field guide" },
	{ "question": "固まる", "answers": [ "かたまる" ], "comment": "to harden; to solidify\nto become firm; to become certain\nto gather (together); to assemble; to huddle together" },
	{ "question": "国王", "answers": [ "こくおう" ], "comment": "king" },
	{ "question": "国立", "answers": [ "こくりつ" ], "comment": "national" },
	{ "question": "国籍", "answers": [ "こくせき" ], "comment": "nationality; citizenship\nnationality (ship, airplane, etc.); registration; flag" },
	{ "question": "園芸", "answers": [ "えんげい" ], "comment": "horticulture; gardening" },
	{ "question": "圧縮", "answers": [ "あっしゅく" ], "comment": "compression; condensation; constriction; compaction" },
	{ "question": "在る", "answers": [ "ある" ], "comment": "to be (usu. of inanimate objects); to exist; to live\nto have\nto be located\nto be equipped with\nto happen; to come about" },
	{ "question": "在学", "answers": [ "ざいがく" ], "comment": "(enrolled) in school" },
	{ "question": "地下水", "answers": [ "ちかすい" ], "comment": "underground water" },
	{ "question": "地名", "answers": [ "ちめい" ], "comment": "place name" },
	{ "question": "地味", "answers": [ "じみ" ], "comment": "plain; simple; subdued; sober\nsoil fertility; product of the soil" },
	{ "question": "地帯", "answers": [ "ちたい" ], "comment": "area; zone; belt (of land)" },
	{ "question": "地点", "answers": [ "ちてん" ], "comment": "site; point on a map; spot" },
	{ "question": "地盤", "answers": [ "じばん" ], "comment": "ground; crust (earth); bed (gravel, river, etc.)\nfoundation (building, etc.); base\nconstituency; power base; support (electoral); footing; foothold" },
	{ "question": "地質", "answers": [ "ちしつ" ], "comment": "geological features\nquality of a fabric or cloth; texture of a fabric" },
	{ "question": "坊さん", "answers": [ "ぼうさん" ], "comment": "Buddhist priest; monk\nboy" },
	{ "question": "坊っちゃん", "answers": [ "ぼっちゃん" ], "comment": "son (of others)\nyoung master\ngreen young man from a well-to-do family" },
	{ "question": "坊や", "answers": [ "ぼうや" ], "comment": "boy" },
	{ "question": "垂直", "answers": [ "すいちょく" ], "comment": "vertical\nperpendicular" },
	{ "question": "垣根", "answers": [ "かきね" ], "comment": "hedge; fence" },
	{ "question": "埋める", "answers": [ "うめる" ], "comment": "to cover; to bury (e.g. one's face in hands); to submerge\nto fill (completely); to stuff; to pack; to cram; to fill up\nto bury (e.g. in the ground)\nto fill up (e.g. audience fills a hall); to cause to be packed\nto plug (a gap); to stop (a gap); to bridge (a difference, a gap); to fill (a seat, a vacant position); to fill out\nto make up for (a loss, shortage, etc.); to make amends; to compensate for\nto put cold water (in a bath)\nto cover; to scatter something over" },
	{ "question": "執筆", "answers": [ "しっぴつ" ], "comment": "writing (e.g. as a profession)" },
	{ "question": "基地", "answers": [ "きち" ], "comment": "base (military, expedition, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "基準", "answers": [ "きじゅん" ], "comment": "standard; basis; criterion; norm; reference; datum" },
	{ "question": "基盤", "answers": [ "きばん" ], "comment": "foundation; basis; base; footing; infrastructure\nbedrock\nsubstrate (circuit board)" },
	{ "question": "基礎", "answers": [ "きそ" ], "comment": "foundation; basis" },
	{ "question": "塊", "answers": [ "かたまり" ], "comment": "lump; mass; bundle; clump; clod; cluster\ngroup; crowd\nembodiment (of an idea, quality, feeling etc.); personification" },
	{ "question": "塞がる", "answers": [ "ふさがる" ], "comment": "to be closed; to be blocked; to be healed (e.g. wound); to be shut up\nto be clogged; to be plugged up\nto be occupied; to be taken (e.g. accommodation)" },
	{ "question": "塞ぐ", "answers": [ "ふさぐ" ], "comment": "to stop up; to close up; to block (up); to plug up; to shut up; to cover (ears, eyes, etc.); to close (eyes, mouth)\nto stand in the way; to obstruct\nto occupy; to fill up; to take up\nto perform one's role; to do one's duty\nto feel depressed; to mope" },
	{ "question": "塩辛い", "answers": [ "しおからい" ], "comment": "salty (taste); briny" },
	{ "question": "境界", "answers": [ "きょうかい" ], "comment": "boundary" },
	{ "question": "増やす", "answers": [ "ふやす" ], "comment": "to increase; to add to; to augment" },
	{ "question": "増大", "answers": [ "ぞうだい" ], "comment": "enlargement; increase" },
	{ "question": "増減", "answers": [ "ぞうげん" ], "comment": "increase and decrease; fluctuation" },
	{ "question": "墨", "answers": [ "すみ" ], "comment": "sumi; India ink; Chinese ink; ink stick; ink-cake\nsquid ink; octopus ink\ncarpenter's inking string\nMexico" },
	{ "question": "売り切れ", "answers": [ "うりきれ" ], "comment": "sold-out" },
	{ "question": "売り切れる", "answers": [ "うりきれる" ], "comment": "to be sold out" },
	{ "question": "売上", "answers": [ "うりあげ" ], "comment": "amount sold; sales; proceeds; takings; turnover" },
	{ "question": "売店", "answers": [ "ばいてん" ], "comment": "shop; stand" },
	{ "question": "売行き", "answers": [ "うれゆき" ], "comment": "sales; demand" },
	{ "question": "売買", "answers": [ "ばいばい" ], "comment": "trade; buying and selling; trafficking (e.g. of humans, arms, drugs); dealing" },
	{ "question": "夕刊", "answers": [ "ゆうかん" ], "comment": "evening paper" },
	{ "question": "夕日", "answers": [ "ゆうひ" ], "comment": "evening sun; setting sun" },
	{ "question": "夕立", "answers": [ "ゆうだち" ], "comment": "(sudden) evening shower (rain)" },
	{ "question": "外れる", "answers": [ "はずれる" ], "comment": "to be disconnected; to get out of place; to be off; to be out (e.g. of gear)" },
	{ "question": "外科", "answers": [ "げか" ], "comment": "surgery\ndepartment of surgery (hospital, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "外部", "answers": [ "がいぶ" ], "comment": "the outside\nexternal" },
	{ "question": "夜行", "answers": [ "やこう" ], "comment": "walking around at night; night train; night travel" },
	{ "question": "夜間", "answers": [ "やかん" ], "comment": "at night; nighttime" },
	{ "question": "大して", "answers": [ "たいして" ], "comment": "(not so) much; (not) very" },
	{ "question": "大学院", "answers": [ "だいがくいん" ], "comment": "graduate school" },
	{ "question": "大小", "answers": [ "だいしょう" ], "comment": "sizes (various); large and small\ndaisho (matched pair of long and short swords)\nlarge and small drums\nlong months and short months\nsic bo (Macau dice game); tai sai; dai siu; big and small" },
	{ "question": "大層", "answers": [ "たいそう" ], "comment": "very; extremely; exceedingly; greatly; terribly\nextreme; excessive; great many; large number of\nsplended; impressive; tremendous; immense\nexaggerated" },
	{ "question": "大工", "answers": [ "だいく" ], "comment": "carpenter" },
	{ "question": "大木", "answers": [ "たいぼく" ], "comment": "large tree" },
	{ "question": "大通り", "answers": [ "おおどおり" ], "comment": "main street" },
	{ "question": "天皇", "answers": [ "てんのう", "すめらぎ" ], "comment": "Emperor of Japan" },
	{ "question": "太鼓", "answers": [ "たいこ" ], "comment": "drum" },
	{ "question": "夫妻", "answers": [ "ふさい" ], "comment": "man and wife; married couple" },
	{ "question": "失恋", "answers": [ "しつれん" ], "comment": "disappointed love; broken heart; unrequited love; being lovelorn" },
	{ "question": "女の人", "answers": [ "おんなのひと" ], "comment": "woman" },
	{ "question": "女房", "answers": [ "にょうぼう" ], "comment": "wife (esp. one's own wife)\ncourt lady; female court attache; woman who served at the imperial palace\nwoman (esp. as a love interest)" },
	{ "question": "好き好き", "answers": [ "すきずき" ], "comment": "matter of taste" },
	{ "question": "好き嫌い", "answers": [ "すききらい" ], "comment": "likes and dislikes; pickiness (about food); choosiness; fussiness; tastes; preferences" },
	{ "question": "妥当", "answers": [ "だとう" ], "comment": "valid; proper; right; appropriate; reasonable" },
	{ "question": "妨げる", "answers": [ "さまたげる" ], "comment": "to disturb; to prevent; to obstruct; to hinder" },
	{ "question": "始めに", "answers": [ "はじめに" ], "comment": "first; firstly; first of all; to begin with; in the beginning; at the beginning\nIntroduction; Preface" },
	{ "question": "始終", "answers": [ "しじゅう" ], "comment": "continuously; from beginning to end; from first to last" },
	{ "question": "姓", "answers": [ "せい" ], "comment": "surname; family name\nhereditary title (used in ancient Japan to denote rank and political standing)\nhereditary title (used in ancient Japan to denote rank and political standing)\nclan" },
	{ "question": "姿勢", "answers": [ "しせい" ], "comment": "attitude; posture; stance; approach; carriage (of the body)" },
	{ "question": "威張る", "answers": [ "いばる" ], "comment": "to put on airs; to act big; to throw one's weight about; to be overbearing; to be domineering; to be bossy; to be pushy; to be proud; to be haughty; to be arrogant; to swagger; to boast; to brag" },
	{ "question": "娯楽", "answers": [ "ごらく" ], "comment": "pleasure; amusement" },
	{ "question": "嫌", "answers": [ "いや" ], "comment": "disagreeable; detestable; unpleasant; reluctant" },
	{ "question": "嫌い", "answers": [ "きらい" ], "comment": "dislike; hate\nsuspicion; tendency; smack (of)\ndistinction; discrimination\ndislike; hatred; fear" },
	{ "question": "嫌がる", "answers": [ "いやがる" ], "comment": "to hate; to dislike" },
	{ "question": "子孫", "answers": [ "しそん" ], "comment": "descendant; posterity; offspring" },
	{ "question": "存じる", "answers": [ "ぞんじる" ], "comment": "to think, feel, consider, know, etc." },
	{ "question": "存ずる", "answers": [ "ぞんずる" ], "comment": "to think, feel, consider, know, etc." },
	{ "question": "孝行", "answers": [ "こうこう" ], "comment": "filial piety" },
	{ "question": "季節", "answers": [ "きせつ" ], "comment": "season" },
	{ "question": "学会", "answers": [ "がっかい" ], "comment": "scientific society; academic meeting; academic conference" },
	{ "question": "学力", "answers": [ "がくりょく" ], "comment": "scholarly ability; scholarship; knowledge; literary ability" },
	{ "question": "学年", "answers": [ "がくねん" ], "comment": "academic year; school year\nyear in school; grade in school" },
	{ "question": "学科", "answers": [ "がっか" ], "comment": "study subject; course of study\ndepartment (university, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "学級", "answers": [ "がっきゅう" ], "comment": "(school) class" },
	{ "question": "学術", "answers": [ "がくじゅつ" ], "comment": "science; learning; scholarship; arts and sciences; academic pursuits" },
	{ "question": "学部", "answers": [ "がくぶ" ], "comment": "department of a university\nundergraduate (course, program, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "安易", "answers": [ "あんい" ], "comment": "easy; simple\neasy-going" },
	{ "question": "官庁", "answers": [ "かんちょう" ], "comment": "government office; government agency; authorities" },
	{ "question": "定休日", "answers": [ "ていきゅうび" ], "comment": "regular holiday; fixed day off; regular closing day" },
	{ "question": "定価", "answers": [ "ていか" ], "comment": "list price; regular price; established price" },
	{ "question": "定員", "answers": [ "ていいん" ], "comment": "fixed number of regular personnel; staff quota; complement\ncapacity (of boat, hall, aeroplane, airplane, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "定期券", "answers": [ "ていきけん" ], "comment": "commuter pass; season ticket" },
	{ "question": "定規", "answers": [ "じょうぎ" ], "comment": "(measuring) ruler" },
	{ "question": "宛名", "answers": [ "あてな" ], "comment": "(addressee's) name; (recipient's) name and address" },
	{ "question": "実る", "answers": [ "みのる" ], "comment": "to bear fruit; to ripen" },
	{ "question": "実例", "answers": [ "じつれい" ], "comment": "example; illustration; precedent" },
	{ "question": "実力", "answers": [ "じつりょく" ], "comment": "(real) ability; true strength; merit; efficiency; competency\narms; force" },
	{ "question": "実感", "answers": [ "じっかん" ], "comment": "real feeling; actual feeling\nto actually feel; to have a real feeling (that ...); to experience personally" },
	{ "question": "実物", "answers": [ "じつぶつ" ], "comment": "real thing; original; actual\nornamental plant used primarily for the visual effect of its fruit" },
	{ "question": "実用", "answers": [ "じつよう" ], "comment": "practical use; utility" },
	{ "question": "実績", "answers": [ "じっせき" ], "comment": "achievements; actual results; accomplishments; past results; track record" },
	{ "question": "実習", "answers": [ "じっしゅう" ], "comment": "practice; practising; training (esp. practical and hands-on); drill" },
	{ "question": "客席", "answers": [ "きゃくせき" ], "comment": "guest seating (e.g. theater, stadium); passenger seat (e.g. taxi)\naudience" },
	{ "question": "客間", "answers": [ "きゃくま" ], "comment": "parlor; parlour; guest room" },
	{ "question": "宣伝", "answers": [ "せんでん" ], "comment": "publicity; advertisement; advertising; propaganda" },
	{ "question": "宴会", "answers": [ "えんかい" ], "comment": "party; banquet; reception; feast; dinner" },
	{ "question": "家主", "answers": [ "やぬし" ], "comment": "landlord; landlady\nhouse owner; home owner; head of the household" },
	{ "question": "家屋", "answers": [ "かおく" ], "comment": "house; building" },
	{ "question": "容器", "answers": [ "ようき" ], "comment": "container; vessel" },
	{ "question": "容積", "answers": [ "ようせき" ], "comment": "capacity; volume" },
	{ "question": "寄せる", "answers": [ "よせる" ], "comment": "to come near; to let someone approach\nto bring near; to bring together; to collect; to gather\nto deliver (opinion, news, etc.); to send (e.g. a letter); to contribute; to donate\nto let someone drop by\nto add (numbers)\nto have feelings for (love, goodwill, trust, etc.)\nto rely upon for a time; to depend on\nto use as a pretext\nto put aside\nto press; to push; to force\nto include; to welcome (in a group); to let in" },
	{ "question": "寒帯", "answers": [ "かんたい" ], "comment": "frigid zone" },
	{ "question": "寝台", "answers": [ "しんだい" ], "comment": "bed; couch" },
	{ "question": "寝巻", "answers": [ "ねまき" ], "comment": "sleep-wear; nightclothes; pyjamas; pajamas; nightgown; nightdress" },
	{ "question": "寝間着", "answers": [ "ねまき" ], "comment": "sleep-wear; nightclothes; pyjamas; pajamas; nightgown; nightdress" },
	{ "question": "寮", "answers": [ "りょう" ], "comment": "hostel; dormitory\nbureau (government department beneath a ministry under the ritsuryo system)\noffice; official\nchief; head" },
	{ "question": "寸法", "answers": [ "すんぽう" ], "comment": "measurement; size; extent; dimension\nplan; intention; arrangement; schedule" },
	{ "question": "寺院", "answers": [ "じいん" ], "comment": "temple" },
	{ "question": "対照", "answers": [ "たいしょう" ], "comment": "contrast; antithesis; comparison" },
	{ "question": "対立", "answers": [ "たいりつ" ], "comment": "confrontation; opposition; antagonism" },
	{ "question": "対策", "answers": [ "たいさく" ], "comment": "measure; provision; step; countermeasure; counterplan; countermove" },
	{ "question": "寿命", "answers": [ "じゅみょう" ], "comment": "life span" },
	{ "question": "封筒", "answers": [ "ふうとう" ], "comment": "envelope" },
	{ "question": "専制", "answers": [ "せんせい" ], "comment": "despotism; autocracy" },
	{ "question": "射す", "answers": [ "さす" ], "comment": "to shine" },
	{ "question": "将棋", "answers": [ "しょうぎ" ], "comment": "shogi; Japanese chess; xianqi" },
	{ "question": "小便", "answers": [ "しょうべん", "しょんべん" ], "comment": "urine; piss; pee\nbreaking a contract" },
	{ "question": "小学生", "answers": [ "しょうがくせい" ], "comment": "elementary school student; primary school student; grade school student" },
	{ "question": "小指", "answers": [ "こゆび" ], "comment": "little finger; pinky\nlittle toe" },
	{ "question": "小数", "answers": [ "しょうすう" ], "comment": "fraction (part of); decimal fraction" },
	{ "question": "小父さん", "answers": [ "おじさん" ], "comment": "uncle\nold man; mister (vocative)\nmanybar goatfish (Parupeneus multifasciatus)" },
	{ "question": "小遣い", "answers": [ "こづかい" ], "comment": "pocket money; spending money; pin money; allowance" },
	{ "question": "就任", "answers": [ "しゅうにん" ], "comment": "inauguration; assumption of office" },
	{ "question": "屋外", "answers": [ "おくがい" ], "comment": "outdoors; alfresco\noutside near the door to one's home" },
	{ "question": "展開", "answers": [ "てんかい" ], "comment": "development; evolution; progressing; unfolding\nexpansion; spreading out; extending; deployment; building up\nexpansion" },
	{ "question": "属する", "answers": [ "ぞくする" ], "comment": "to belong to; to come under; to be affiliated with; to be subject to\nto entrust\nto send (a message, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "山林", "answers": [ "さんりん" ], "comment": "mountain forest; forest on a mountain; montane forest\nmountains and forest" },
	{ "question": "岬", "answers": [ "みさき" ], "comment": "small peninsula\ncape (on coast)" },
	{ "question": "峠", "answers": [ "とうげ" ], "comment": "ridge; (mountain) pass; difficult part" },
	{ "question": "崩す", "answers": [ "くずす" ], "comment": "to destroy; to demolish; to pull down; to tear down; to level\nto disturb; to put into disorder; to throw off balance; to make shaky\nto relax (one's pose); to make oneself at ease\nto break (a bill); to change; to make change\nto write in cursive style; to write in running style\nto break into a smile; to let off a smile\nto lower (a price)" },
	{ "question": "崩れる", "answers": [ "くずれる" ], "comment": "to collapse; to crumble\nto get out of shape; to lose one's shape; to become disorganized; to become untidy\nto break down; to be thrown into disarray\nto crash (stock market); to slump; to decline\nto break money into small change\nto turn bad (e.g. weather); to change for the worse; to deteriorate" },
	{ "question": "巡る", "answers": [ "めぐる" ], "comment": "to go around\nto return\nto surround\nto concern (usu. of disputes)" },
	{ "question": "巡査", "answers": [ "じゅんさ" ], "comment": "police officer; policeman; constable" },
	{ "question": "工事", "answers": [ "こうじ" ], "comment": "construction work; construction; work (related to construction, e.g. painting, concrete-pouring, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "工員", "answers": [ "こういん" ], "comment": "factory worker" },
	{ "question": "工夫", "answers": [ "くふう" ], "comment": "scheme; device; scheming; devising; figuring out; coming up with; solving ingeniously\ndedication to spiritual improvement (esp. through Zen meditation)\nlabourer; laborer; blue-collar worker" },
	{ "question": "工芸", "answers": [ "こうげい" ], "comment": "industrial arts; craft" },
	{ "question": "差し引き", "answers": [ "さしひき" ], "comment": "deduction; subtraction; balance\nebb and flow; rise and fall" },
	{ "question": "差し支え", "answers": [ "さしつかえ" ], "comment": "hindrance; impediment" },
	{ "question": "巻く", "answers": [ "まく" ], "comment": "to wind; to coil; to roll; to wear (e.g. turban, scarf)\nto envelope; to shroud\nto outflank; to skirt\nto link (verse)\nto move ahead (three hours, etc.); to move up" },
	{ "question": "帰す", "answers": [ "かえす" ], "comment": "to send (someone) back; to send (someone) home\nto come to (in the end); to end in\nto attribute; to blame" },
	{ "question": "干す", "answers": [ "ほす" ], "comment": "to air; to dry; to desiccate\nto drain (off)\nto drink up\nto deprive of a role, job, etc. (usu. in the passive)" },
	{ "question": "平仮名", "answers": [ "ひらがな" ], "comment": "hiragana; cursive Japanese syllabary used primarily for native Japanese words (esp. function words, inflections, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "平凡", "answers": [ "へいぼん" ], "comment": "common; commonplace; ordinary; mediocre" },
	{ "question": "平日", "answers": [ "へいじつ" ], "comment": "weekday; ordinary days (i.e. non-holiday)\nkanji radical 73" },
	{ "question": "平気", "answers": [ "へいき" ], "comment": "coolness; calmness; composure; unconcern\nall right; OK; okay" },
	{ "question": "平野", "answers": [ "へいや" ], "comment": "plain; open field" },
	{ "question": "年度", "answers": [ "ねんど" ], "comment": "fiscal year (usu. April 1 to March 31 in Japan); financial year\nacademic year; school year\nproduct year" },
	{ "question": "幼児", "answers": [ "ようじ" ], "comment": "infant; baby; child\nchild over 1 but not yet of school age" },
	{ "question": "幼稚", "answers": [ "ようち" ], "comment": "infancy\nchildish; infantile; immature; primitive" },
	{ "question": "幼稚園", "answers": [ "ようちえん" ], "comment": "kindergarten" },
	{ "question": "幾分", "answers": [ "いくぶん" ], "comment": "somewhat; to some extent; to some degree\nsome; part; portion" },
	{ "question": "広々", "answers": [ "ひろびろ" ], "comment": "extensive; spacious\nextensive; spacious" },
	{ "question": "広げる", "answers": [ "ひろげる" ], "comment": "to spread; to extend; to expand; to enlarge; to widen; to broaden\nto unfold; to open; to unroll; to unwrap\nto scatter about; to spread around\nto make flourish; to cause to prosper" },
	{ "question": "広さ", "answers": [ "ひろさ" ], "comment": "extent" },
	{ "question": "広める", "answers": [ "ひろめる" ], "comment": "to spread; to propagate; to popularize; to disseminate\nto broaden; to extend; to widen; to enlarge" },
	{ "question": "広場", "answers": [ "ひろば" ], "comment": "plaza; (public) square; piazza; forum; open space" },
	{ "question": "床の間", "answers": [ "とこのま" ], "comment": "tokonoma (alcove where art or flowers are displayed)" },
	{ "question": "床屋", "answers": [ "とこや" ], "comment": "barbershop; barber" },
	{ "question": "店屋", "answers": [ "みせや" ], "comment": "store; shop" },
	{ "question": "座布団", "answers": [ "ざぶとん" ], "comment": "zabuton (flat floor cushion used when sitting or kneeling; usu. rectangular)" },
	{ "question": "座敷", "answers": [ "ざしき" ], "comment": "tatami room; tatami mat room; formal Japanese room\ndinner party in a tatami room (esp. when a geisha or maiko attends)" },
	{ "question": "延ばす", "answers": [ "のばす" ], "comment": "to grow long (e.g. hair, nails)\nto lengthen; to extend; to stretch\nto reach out; to hold out\nto straighten; to smooth out\nto spread evenly (dough, cream, etc.)\nto dilute; to thin out\nto postpone\nto prolong\nto strengthen; to develop; to expand" },
	{ "question": "延びる", "answers": [ "のびる" ], "comment": "to stretch; to extend; to lengthen; to spread\nto make progress; to grow (beard, body height)\nto grow stale (soba)\nto be straightened; to be flattened; to be smoothed\nto be exhausted\nto be postponed; to be prolonged" },
	{ "question": "延長", "answers": [ "えんちょう" ], "comment": "extension; elongation; prolongation; lengthening\nEnchou era (923.4.11-931.4.26)" },
	{ "question": "建つ", "answers": [ "たつ" ], "comment": "to be erected; to be built" },
	{ "question": "引き止める", "answers": [ "ひきとめる" ], "comment": "to detain; to check; to restrain" },
	{ "question": "引っ掛かる", "answers": [ "ひっかかる" ], "comment": "to be caught in; to be stuck in\nto stop by; to drop in for a short visit; to be delayed; to take time\nto get mixed up in (trouble); to get entangled in (a problem); to be involved with\nto fall for (a trick); to be deceived; to be cheated\nto be on one's mind; to worry one; to be bothered by; to feel uneasy\nto be obstructed; to be hindered\nto splash" },
	{ "question": "引っ繰り返す", "answers": [ "ひっくりかえす" ], "comment": "to turn over; to turn upside down; to turn up; to turn inside out; to turn out\nto knock over; to tip over\nto overturn (e.g. a decision); to upset; to reverse" },
	{ "question": "引っ繰り返る", "answers": [ "ひっくりかえる" ], "comment": "to be overturned; to be upset; to topple over; to be reversed; to fall down; to tip over" },
	{ "question": "引っ込む", "answers": [ "ひっこむ" ], "comment": "to draw back; to sink; to cave in\nto be set back (e.g. from a road)\nto withdraw (e.g. from the public eye); to retire to (somewhere); to stay indoors; to butt out; to stay out of it" },
	{ "question": "引出す", "answers": [ "ひきだす" ], "comment": "to pull out; to take out; to draw out; to withdraw" },
	{ "question": "引分け", "answers": [ "ひきわけ" ], "comment": "draw (in competition); tie game" },
	{ "question": "引力", "answers": [ "いんりょく" ], "comment": "attraction (e.g. magnetic, gravitation); affinity; gravitational pull\nattractiveness; magnetism" },
	{ "question": "引受る", "answers": [ "ひきうける" ], "comment": "to take on; to undertake; to accept; to take charge of; to assume responsibility for\nto take over; to inherit\nto guarantee; to vouch for\nto contract (a disease)" },
	{ "question": "引算", "answers": [ "ひきざん" ], "comment": "subtraction" },
	{ "question": "引越し", "answers": [ "ひっこし" ], "comment": "moving (dwelling, office, etc.); changing residence" },
	{ "question": "引返す", "answers": [ "ひきかえす" ], "comment": "to turn back; to go back; to come back; to return; to retrace one's steps" },
	{ "question": "弱点", "answers": [ "じゃくてん" ], "comment": "weak point; weakness; shortcoming; defect; flaw; sore spot; tender spot" },
	{ "question": "張り切る", "answers": [ "はりきる" ], "comment": "to be in high spirits; to be full of vigor (vigour); to be enthusiastic; to be eager; to stretch to breaking point" },
	{ "question": "強化", "answers": [ "きょうか" ], "comment": "strengthening; intensifying; reinforcement; solidification" },
	{ "question": "強引", "answers": [ "ごういん" ], "comment": "overbearing; coercive; pushy; forcible; high-handed" },
	{ "question": "強気", "answers": [ "つよき" ], "comment": "confident; assured; self-assured; firm; strong; cocksure\nbullish (e.g. market)\ngreat; grand\nobstinate; stubborn" },
	{ "question": "当日", "answers": [ "とうじつ" ], "comment": "appointed day; very day" },
	{ "question": "当番", "answers": [ "とうばん" ], "comment": "being on duty" },
	{ "question": "形容動詞", "answers": [ "けいようどうし" ], "comment": "na-adjective (adj-na); quasi-adjective; adjectival noun; nominal adjective" },
	{ "question": "形容詞", "answers": [ "けいようし" ], "comment": "adjective; i-adjective (in Japanese)" },
	{ "question": "形式", "answers": [ "けいしき" ], "comment": "form (as opposed to substance); formality\nmethod; system; style\nformat; mode; appearance; form (something takes)\nmath expression" },
	{ "question": "彫る", "answers": [ "ほる" ], "comment": "to carve; to engrave; to sculpt; to chisel\nto tattoo" },
	{ "question": "彫刻", "answers": [ "ちょうこく" ], "comment": "carving; engraving; sculpture" },
	{ "question": "役人", "answers": [ "やくにん" ], "comment": "government official" },
	{ "question": "役所", "answers": [ "やくしょ" ], "comment": "government office; public office" },
	{ "question": "役目", "answers": [ "やくめ" ], "comment": "duty; role; function" },
	{ "question": "役者", "answers": [ "やくしゃ" ], "comment": "actor; actress" },
	{ "question": "往復", "answers": [ "おうふく" ], "comment": "making a round trip; going and returning; coming and going\nround-trip ticket; return ticket\ncorrespondence; exchanging (letters)\nsocializing; visiting one another" },
	{ "question": "待ち合わせる", "answers": [ "まちあわせる" ], "comment": "to rendezvous; to meet at a prearranged place and time; to arrange to meet" },
	{ "question": "待合室", "answers": [ "まちあいしつ" ], "comment": "waiting room" },
	{ "question": "後輩", "answers": [ "こうはい" ], "comment": "junior (at work, school, etc.); younger people; younger student" },
	{ "question": "従姉妹", "answers": [ "いとこ" ], "comment": "cousin (female)" },
	{ "question": "御中 (not おなか)", "answers": [ "おんちゅう" ] },
	{ "question": "御免", "answers": [ "ごめん" ], "comment": "your pardon; declining (something); dismissal; permission" },
	{ "question": "御手洗", "answers": [ "おてあらい" ], "comment": "font of purifying water placed at the entrance of a shrine" },
	{ "question": "御無沙汰", "answers": [ "ごぶさた" ], "comment": "not writing or contacting for a while; neglecting (failing) to write (call, visit, etc.); long silence" },
	{ "question": "御覧", "answers": [ "ごらん" ], "comment": "(please) try to\n(please) look\nseeing; looking; watching" },
	{ "question": "御辞儀", "answers": [ "おじぎ" ], "comment": "bow; bowing" },
	{ "question": "循環", "answers": [ "じゅんかん" ], "comment": "circulation; rotation; cycle" },
	{ "question": "心当たり", "answers": [ "こころあたり" ], "comment": "having some knowledge of; happening to know" },
	{ "question": "心得る", "answers": [ "こころえる" ], "comment": "to know; to understand; to be aware of; to regard as; to take for\nto consent; to agree" },
	{ "question": "心身", "answers": [ "しんしん" ], "comment": "mind and body" },
	{ "question": "必需品", "answers": [ "ひつじゅひん" ], "comment": "necessities; necessary article; requisite; essentials" },
	{ "question": "応ずる", "answers": [ "おうずる" ], "comment": "to answer; to respond; to meet\nto satisfy; to accept" },
	{ "question": "応対", "answers": [ "おうたい" ], "comment": "receiving; dealing with" },
	{ "question": "応接", "answers": [ "おうせつ" ], "comment": "reception" },
	{ "question": "応援", "answers": [ "おうえん" ], "comment": "aid; assistance; help; reinforcement; rooting; barracking; support; cheering" },
	{ "question": "応用", "answers": [ "おうよう" ], "comment": "application; put to practical use\napplied" },
	{ "question": "快晴", "answers": [ "かいせい" ], "comment": "clear weather; cloudless weather; good weather" },
	{ "question": "思いっ切り", "answers": [ "おもいっきり" ], "comment": "with all one's strength; with all one's heart; resignation; resolution" },
	{ "question": "思い付く", "answers": [ "おもいつく" ], "comment": "to think of; to hit upon; to come into one's mind; to be struck with an idea\nto remember; to recall" },
	{ "question": "思い掛けない", "answers": [ "おもいがけない" ], "comment": "unexpected; contrary to expectations; by chance; casual" },
	{ "question": "思い込む", "answers": [ "おもいこむ" ], "comment": "to be under impression that; to be convinced that; to imagine that; to set one's heart on; to be bent on" },
	{ "question": "怠る", "answers": [ "おこたる" ], "comment": "to be negligent in doing something; to shirk; to be off one's guard" },
	{ "question": "性別", "answers": [ "せいべつ" ], "comment": "distinction by sex; sex; gender" },
	{ "question": "性能", "answers": [ "せいのう" ], "comment": "ability; performance; efficiency" },
	{ "question": "性質", "answers": [ "せいしつ" ], "comment": "nature; property; disposition" },
	{ "question": "怪しい", "answers": [ "あやしい" ], "comment": "suspicious; dubious; doubtful; dodgy; suspicious (referring to a potential amorous relation); dangerous (e.g. financial situation); ominous (e.g. weather); strange; shady; fishy\ncharming; bewitching; mysterious" },
	{ "question": "恋しい", "answers": [ "こいしい" ], "comment": "yearned for; longed for; missed" },
	{ "question": "恐縮", "answers": [ "きょうしゅく" ], "comment": "feeling obliged; being grateful; being thankful; being sorry; being ashamed\nshrinking back in fear" },
	{ "question": "恨み", "answers": [ "うらみ" ], "comment": "resentment; grudge; malice; bitterness\nmatter for regret; regret" },
	{ "question": "恨む", "answers": [ "うらむ" ], "comment": "to resent; to curse; to feel bitter; to blame; to bear a grudge\nto regret" },
	{ "question": "恩恵", "answers": [ "おんけい" ], "comment": "grace; favor; favour; blessing; benefit" },
	{ "question": "恵まれる", "answers": [ "めぐまれる" ], "comment": "to be blessed with; to be rich in; to abound in" },
	{ "question": "悔しい", "answers": [ "くやしい" ], "comment": "vexing; annoying; frustrating; regrettable; mortifying" },
	{ "question": "悔やむ", "answers": [ "くやむ" ], "comment": "to mourn; to lament\nto be sorry; to regret; to repent" },
	{ "question": "悠々", "answers": [ "ゆうゆう" ], "comment": "quiet; calm; leisurely\ndistant; far off; boundless; endless\neasily; comfortably; without difficulty" },
	{ "question": "惜しい", "answers": [ "おしい" ], "comment": "regrettable; disappointing\nprecious; dear; valuable\ntoo good for; deserving better\nalmost but not quite" },
	{ "question": "意地悪", "answers": [ "いじわる" ], "comment": "malicious; ill-tempered; unkind" },
	{ "question": "意義", "answers": [ "いぎ" ], "comment": "meaning; significance" },
	{ "question": "感ずる", "answers": [ "かんずる" ], "comment": "to feel; to sense" },
	{ "question": "感想", "answers": [ "かんそう" ], "comment": "impressions; thoughts" },
	{ "question": "感激", "answers": [ "かんげき" ], "comment": "deep emotion; impression; inspiration" },
	{ "question": "慰める", "answers": [ "なぐさめる" ], "comment": "to comfort; to console; to amuse" },
	{ "question": "憎い", "answers": [ "にくい" ], "comment": "hateful; abominable; poor-looking; detestable\namazing; fantastic; admirable; lovely; wonderful" },
	{ "question": "憎む", "answers": [ "にくむ" ], "comment": "to hate; to detest" },
	{ "question": "憎らしい", "answers": [ "にくらしい" ], "comment": "odious; hateful" },
	{ "question": "憧れる", "answers": [ "あこがれる" ], "comment": "to long for; to yearn after; to admire; to be attracted by" },
	{ "question": "懐かしい", "answers": [ "なつかしい" ], "comment": "dear; desired; missed" },
	{ "question": "成分", "answers": [ "せいぶん" ], "comment": "ingredient; component; composition" },
	{ "question": "成立", "answers": [ "せいりつ" ], "comment": "coming into existence; arrangements; establishment; conclusion; completion\nto come into existence; to be true; to hold (i.e. hold true)" },
	{ "question": "戸棚", "answers": [ "とだな" ], "comment": "cupboard; locker; closet; wardrobe; cabinet" },
	{ "question": "所々", "answers": [ "ところどころ" ], "comment": "here and there; some parts (of something); several places" },
	{ "question": "扇ぐ", "answers": [ "あおぐ" ], "comment": "to fan\nto incite; to instigate" },
	{ "question": "扇子", "answers": [ "せんす" ], "comment": "folding fan" },
	{ "question": "扇風機", "answers": [ "せんぷうき" ], "comment": "electric fan" },
	{ "question": "手入れ", "answers": [ "ていれ" ], "comment": "care; looking after; repair; maintenance; tending; trimming; grooming\n(police) raid; crackdown" },
	{ "question": "手前", "answers": [ "てまえ" ], "comment": "before; this side\none's standpoint; one's appearance\nwe\nyou\nyou (used by young males)\noneself" },
	{ "question": "手帳", "answers": [ "てちょう" ], "comment": "notebook; memo pad; (pocket) diary\ncertificate\nidentification card" },
	{ "question": "手拭い", "answers": [ "てぬぐい" ], "comment": "(hand) towel" },
	{ "question": "手洗い", "answers": [ "てあらい" ], "comment": "washing one's hands; water (or basin, etc.) for washing one's hands\nrestroom; lavatory; toilet\nhand-washing (laundry, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "手続き", "answers": [ "てつづき" ], "comment": "procedure; (legal) process; formalities" },
	{ "question": "手頃", "answers": [ "てごろ" ], "comment": "moderate; handy; convenient; reasonable" },
	{ "question": "手首", "answers": [ "てくび" ], "comment": "wrist" },
	{ "question": "打ち消す", "answers": [ "うちけす" ], "comment": "to deny; to contradict\nto negate (esp. a sound); to drown out" },
	{ "question": "打合せ", "answers": [ "うちあわせ" ], "comment": "advance arrangements; preparatory meeting; briefing session\noverlap (of a coat, etc.)\nmaking something match exactly" },
	{ "question": "払い戻す", "answers": [ "はらいもどす" ], "comment": "to repay; to pay back" },
	{ "question": "払い込む", "answers": [ "はらいこむ" ], "comment": "to deposit; to pay in" },
	{ "question": "承る", "answers": [ "うけたまわる" ], "comment": "to hear; to be told; to know\nto receive (order); to undertake; to comply; to take (a reservation, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "投書", "answers": [ "とうしょ" ], "comment": "letter to the editor; letter from a reader; contribution" },
	{ "question": "折角", "answers": [ "せっかく" ], "comment": "with trouble; at great pains\nrare; valuable; precious; long-awaited\nkind; generous\nspecially; especially; expressly" },
	{ "question": "押える", "answers": [ "おさえる" ], "comment": "to pin something down; to hold something down; to hold something back; to stop; to restrain; to curb\nto seize; to grasp; to arrest\nto gain control of something; to govern; to keep down (e.g. information); to suppress\nto catch happening; to determine (important points); to find (proof); to understand" },
	{ "question": "抽象", "answers": [ "ちゅうしょう" ], "comment": "abstract" },
	{ "question": "担ぐ", "answers": [ "かつぐ" ], "comment": "to shoulder; to carry on one's shoulder\nto nominate for a position; to choose as a representative\nto take (someone) for a ride; to deceive; to take in\nto be caught up in superstition" },
	{ "question": "拝む", "answers": [ "おがむ" ], "comment": "to assume the posture of praying; to press the palms and fingers of both hands together; to do reverence (e.g. before a statue of the Buddha); to pay one's respects\nto beg; to make a supplication\nto see (something or someone of high status)" },
	{ "question": "拡充", "answers": [ "かくじゅう" ], "comment": "expansion" },
	{ "question": "拡張", "answers": [ "かくちょう" ], "comment": "expansion; extension; enlargement; escape; ESC" },
	{ "question": "括弧", "answers": [ "かっこ" ], "comment": "parentheses; brackets" },
	{ "question": "拭く", "answers": [ "ふく" ], "comment": "to wipe; to dry" },
	{ "question": "持参", "answers": [ "じさん" ], "comment": "bringing; taking; carrying" },
	{ "question": "指定", "answers": [ "してい" ], "comment": "designation; specification; assignment; appointment; pointing at" },
	{ "question": "挙げる", "answers": [ "あげる" ], "comment": "to raise; to elevate\nto do up (one's hair)\nto fly (a kite, etc.); to launch (fireworks, etc.); to surface (a submarine, etc.)\nto land (a boat)\nto show someone (into a room)\nto send someone (away)\nto enrol (one's child in school); to enroll\nto increase (price, quality, status, etc.); to develop (talent, skill); to improve\nto make (a loud sound); to raise (one's voice)\nto earn (something desirable)\nto praise\nto give (an example, etc.); to cite\nto summon up (all of one's energy, etc.)\nto arrest\nto nominate\nto give\nto offer up (incense, a prayer, etc.) to the gods (or Buddha, etc.)\nto bear (a child)\nto conduct (a ceremony, esp. a wedding)\n(of the tide) to come in\nto vomit\nto do for (the sake of someone else)\nto complete ...\nto humbly do ..." },
	{ "question": "挟まる", "answers": [ "はさまる" ], "comment": "to get between; to be caught in" },
	{ "question": "挟む", "answers": [ "はさむ" ], "comment": "to interpose; to hold between; to insert\nto be on either side (e.g. road); to be across (e.g. street, river); to be beyond\nto insert\nto interrupt; to slip in a word\nto harbor (e.g. doubts); to harbour; to entertain (e.g. a theory)" },
	{ "question": "振り仮名", "answers": [ "ふりがな" ], "comment": "furigana; kana over or beside kanji to indicate pronunciation" },
	{ "question": "振舞う", "answers": [ "ふるまう" ], "comment": "to behave; to conduct oneself\nto entertain; to treat someone (to a drink); to make tea for someone (tea ceremony)" },
	{ "question": "挿す", "answers": [ "さす" ], "comment": "to insert; to put in\nto plant (a cutting); to strike\nto arrange (flowers)\nto wear (a sword) in one's belt\nto shut; to close; to lock; to fasten" },
	{ "question": "捕える", "answers": [ "とらえる" ], "comment": "to catch; to capture; to seize; to arrest; to grab; to catch hold of\nto grasp (e.g. meaning); to perceive; to capture (e.g. features)\nto captivate; to move (one's heart)" },
	{ "question": "捕まえる", "answers": [ "つかまえる" ], "comment": "to catch; to arrest; to seize" },
	{ "question": "捕る", "answers": [ "とる" ], "comment": "to take; to catch; to capture" },
	{ "question": "捜す", "answers": [ "さがす" ], "comment": "to search (for something desired, needed); to look for\nto search (for something lost); to seek (a suspect in a crime)" },
	{ "question": "捨てる", "answers": [ "すてる" ], "comment": "to throw away; to cast away; to dump; to discard\nto abandon; to desert; to leave\nto give up; to resign" },
	{ "question": "掃く", "answers": [ "はく" ], "comment": "to sweep; to brush; to gather up" },
	{ "question": "掃除", "answers": [ "そうじ" ], "comment": "cleaning; sweeping; dusting; scrubbing" },
	{ "question": "授業", "answers": [ "じゅぎょう" ], "comment": "lesson; class work; teaching; instruction" },
	{ "question": "掘る", "answers": [ "ほる" ], "comment": "to dig; to excavate; to hollow\nto delve into\nto dig up (e.g. vegetables)\n(for two men) to have anal sex" },
	{ "question": "掛け算", "answers": [ "かけざん" ], "comment": "multiplication" },
	{ "question": "採る", "answers": [ "とる" ], "comment": "to adopt (measure, proposal)\nto pick (e.g. fruit); to catch (e.g. insects); to take (e.g. a sample)\nto assume (attitude)\nto take on (i.e. hire); to engage" },
	{ "question": "採点", "answers": [ "さいてん" ], "comment": "marking; grading; scoring" },
	{ "question": "探る", "answers": [ "さぐる" ], "comment": "to feel around for; to fumble for; to grope for; to search for; to look for\nto investigate; to probe into; to spy on; to sound out\nto explore (parts unknown); to enjoy (natural beauty)" },
	{ "question": "接する", "answers": [ "せっする" ], "comment": "to touch; to come in contact with; to border on; to adjoin; to be adjacent; to be close\nto receive (e.g. visitor); to attend to; to serve; to take care of; to look after; to deal with; to see\nto receive (news); to get; to hear\nto encounter; to come across\nto be tangent to\nto make touch; to bring into contact with; to bring adjacent to; to bring close; to connect" },
	{ "question": "接続", "answers": [ "せつぞく" ], "comment": "connection; attachment; union; join; joint; link\nchanging trains\nconjunction" },
	{ "question": "接近", "answers": [ "せっきん" ], "comment": "getting closer; drawing nearer; approaching\nbeing not much different; being near (age, skill, etc.)\nbecoming close (i.e. friendly); becoming intimate" },
	{ "question": "推定", "answers": [ "すいてい" ], "comment": "presumption; assumption\nestimation" },
	{ "question": "揚げる", "answers": [ "あげる" ], "comment": "to raise; to elevate\nto do up (one's hair)\nto fly (a kite, etc.); to launch (fireworks, etc.); to surface (a submarine, etc.)\nto land (a boat)\nto deep-fry\nto show someone (into a room)\nto summon (for geishas, etc.)\nto send someone (away)\nto enrol (one's child in school); to enroll\nto increase (price, quality, status, etc.); to develop (talent, skill); to improve\nto make (a loud sound); to raise (one's voice)\nto earn (something desirable)\nto praise\nto give (an example, etc.); to cite\nto summon up (all of one's energy, etc.)\nto give\nto offer up (incense, a prayer, etc.) to the gods (or Buddha, etc.)\nto bear (a child)\nto conduct (a ceremony, esp. a wedding)\n(of the tide) to come in\nto vomit\nto do for (the sake of someone else)\nto complete ...\nto humbly do ..." },
	{ "question": "換気", "answers": [ "かんき" ], "comment": "ventilation" },
	{ "question": "損得", "answers": [ "そんとく" ], "comment": "loss and gain; advantage and disadvantage" },
	{ "question": "摩擦", "answers": [ "まさつ" ], "comment": "friction; rubbing; rubdown; chafe" },
	{ "question": "撮る", "answers": [ "とる" ], "comment": "to take (a photo)\nto record (video, audio, etc.); to make (a film)" },
	{ "question": "撮影", "answers": [ "さつえい" ], "comment": "photography (still or motion); photographing; filming; shooting; (video) recording" },
	{ "question": "改めて", "answers": [ "あらためて" ], "comment": "another time; again; over again; once again; anew\nformally; especially; intentionally; deliberately" },
	{ "question": "改める", "answers": [ "あらためる" ], "comment": "to change; to alter; to revise; to replace\nto reform; to correct; to mend; to improve\nto examine; to check; to inspect\nto do properly; to do formally" },
	{ "question": "改札", "answers": [ "かいさつ" ], "comment": "examination of tickets\nticket gate; ticket barrier" },
	{ "question": "改正", "answers": [ "かいせい" ], "comment": "revision; amendment; alteration" },
	{ "question": "改造", "answers": [ "かいぞう" ], "comment": "remodeling; remodelling; restructuring; reconstruction; reshuffling (e.g. cabinet)\nmodding" },
	{ "question": "攻める", "answers": [ "せめる" ], "comment": "to attack; to assault; to assail" },
	{ "question": "放る", "answers": [ "ほうる" ], "comment": "to throw; to toss; to fling\nto throw away; to discard\nto neglect; to abandon; to leave alone; to give up on; to leave undone; to leave unfinished\nto expel (from the body); to excrete; to defecate; to give birth\nto excrete (faeces, urine)\nto get free; to be freed; to be released" },
	{ "question": "放れる", "answers": [ "はなれる" ], "comment": "to get free; to be freed; to be released" },
	{ "question": "政党", "answers": [ "せいとう" ], "comment": "political party" },
	{ "question": "政治", "answers": [ "せいじ" ], "comment": "politics; government" },
	{ "question": "教わる", "answers": [ "おそわる" ], "comment": "to be taught (by); to learn from" },
	{ "question": "教養", "answers": [ "きょうよう" ], "comment": "cultivation; refinement; culture; education" },
	{ "question": "散らかす", "answers": [ "ちらかす" ], "comment": "to scatter around; to leave untidy" },
	{ "question": "散らかる", "answers": [ "ちらかる" ], "comment": "to be in disorder; to lie scattered around" },
	{ "question": "散らす", "answers": [ "ちらす" ], "comment": "to scatter; to cause a shower of\nto disperse; to distribute; to spread\nto resolve (a symptom, condition, etc.); to relieve; to get rid of; to cure\nto distract; to divert\nto do ... wildly (i.e. disorderly or frequently); to do ... all over the place" },
	{ "question": "散る", "answers": [ "ちる" ], "comment": "to fall (e.g. blossoms, leaves)\nto scatter; to be dispersed\nto disappear; to dissolve; to break up\nto spread; to run; to blur\nto die a noble death" },
	{ "question": "敬う", "answers": [ "うやまう" ], "comment": "to show respect; to honour; to honor" },
	{ "question": "敬語", "answers": [ "けいご" ], "comment": "honorific; term of respect; polite expression; honorific language" },
	{ "question": "整う", "answers": [ "ととのう" ], "comment": "to be ready; to be prepared; to be arranged\nto be in order; to be put in order; to be well-ordered; to be well-proportioned; to be harmonious\nto be adjusted; to be regulated; to be refined (e.g. of a face)\nto be settled (e.g. treaty, contract); to be completed" },
	{ "question": "整備", "answers": [ "せいび" ], "comment": "maintenance; servicing\nputting in place; establishment; development; preparation; provision; outfitting" },
	{ "question": "整数", "answers": [ "せいすう" ], "comment": "integer" },
	{ "question": "敷く", "answers": [ "しく" ], "comment": "to spread out; to lay out\nto take a position\nto impose widely (e.g. over a city)" },
	{ "question": "敷地", "answers": [ "しきち" ], "comment": "site; plot; lot; grounds" },
	{ "question": "文体", "answers": [ "ぶんたい" ], "comment": "literary style" },
	{ "question": "文房具", "answers": [ "ぶんぼうぐ" ], "comment": "stationery" },
	{ "question": "文献", "answers": [ "ぶんけん" ], "comment": "literature; books (reference); document" },
	{ "question": "文脈", "answers": [ "ぶんみゃく" ], "comment": "context" },
	{ "question": "文芸", "answers": [ "ぶんげい" ], "comment": "literature; art and literature; belles-lettres" },
	{ "question": "斜", "answers": [ "はす" ], "comment": "slanting; tilted; sloping; diagonal; oblique\nunusual; slanted (view of the world); bad (mood)\ndiagonal" },
	{ "question": "斜め", "answers": [ "ななめ" ], "comment": "slanting; tilted; sloping; diagonal; oblique\nunusual; slanted (view of the world); bad (mood)" },
	{ "question": "斬る", "answers": [ "きる" ], "comment": "to kill (a human) using a blade (sword, machete, knife, etc.); to slice (off); to lop (off); to cut (off)" },
	{ "question": "断定", "answers": [ "だんてい" ], "comment": "conclusion; decision" },
	{ "question": "断水", "answers": [ "だんすい" ], "comment": "suspension of water supply; water outage" },
	{ "question": "新幹線", "answers": [ "しんかんせん" ], "comment": "Shinkansen; bullet train" },
	{ "question": "方程式", "answers": [ "ほうていしき" ], "comment": "equation; formula\nmethod for solving a problem; set way of achieving a particular result" },
	{ "question": "方角", "answers": [ "ほうがく" ], "comment": "direction; way\npoint of the compass; cardinal direction; bearing\nmethod; means; approach" },
	{ "question": "方言", "answers": [ "ほうげん" ], "comment": "dialect" },
	{ "question": "方針", "answers": [ "ほうしん" ], "comment": "objective; plan; policy" },
	{ "question": "方面", "answers": [ "ほうめん" ], "comment": "direction; district; area\nfield (e.g. of study); sphere; quarter; aspect; angle" },
	{ "question": "日にち", "answers": [ "ひにち" ], "comment": "the number of days; date" },
	{ "question": "日の入り", "answers": [ "ひのいり" ], "comment": "sunset" },
	{ "question": "日の出", "answers": [ "ひので" ], "comment": "sunrise" },
	{ "question": "日差し", "answers": [ "ひざし" ], "comment": "sunlight; rays of the sun" },
	{ "question": "日帰り", "answers": [ "ひがえり" ], "comment": "day trip" },
	{ "question": "日当たり", "answers": [ "ひあたり" ], "comment": "exposure to the sun; sunny place\nper day" },
	{ "question": "日時", "answers": [ "にちじ" ], "comment": "date and time" },
	{ "question": "日用品", "answers": [ "にちようひん" ], "comment": "daily necessities" },
	{ "question": "日程", "answers": [ "にってい" ], "comment": "schedule; program; programme; agenda" },
	{ "question": "日課", "answers": [ "にっか" ], "comment": "daily lesson; daily work; daily routine" },
	{ "question": "日陰", "answers": [ "ひかげ" ], "comment": "shade; shadow" },
	{ "question": "早口", "answers": [ "はやくち" ], "comment": "fast-talking; rapid talking" },
	{ "question": "早速", "answers": [ "さっそく" ], "comment": "at once; immediately; without delay; promptly" },
	{ "question": "明き", "answers": [ "あき" ], "comment": "space; room; gap; emptiness\nvacancy; opening; empty seat\nfree time; time to spare\ndisuse; unused thing" },
	{ "question": "明け方", "answers": [ "あけがた" ], "comment": "dawn" },
	{ "question": "映す", "answers": [ "うつす" ], "comment": "to project; to reflect; to cast (shadow)" },
	{ "question": "映る", "answers": [ "うつる" ], "comment": "to be reflected; to harmonize with (harmonise); to come out (photo); to be projected; to be displayed (on a screen)" },
	{ "question": "昼寝", "answers": [ "ひるね" ], "comment": "nap (afternoon); siesta" },
	{ "question": "時速", "answers": [ "じそく" ], "comment": "speed (per hour)" },
	{ "question": "時間割", "answers": [ "じかんわり" ], "comment": "timetable (esp. a weekly school timetable); schedule" },
	{ "question": "普及", "answers": [ "ふきゅう" ], "comment": "diffusion; spread; popularization; promulgation; familiarization" },
	{ "question": "暖まる", "answers": [ "あたたまる" ], "comment": "to warm oneself; to sun oneself; to warm up; to get warm" },
	{ "question": "暖める", "answers": [ "あたためる" ], "comment": "to warm; to heat" },
	{ "question": "暴れる", "answers": [ "あばれる" ], "comment": "to act violently; to rage; to struggle; to be riotous" },
	{ "question": "曲げる", "answers": [ "まげる" ], "comment": "to bend; to crook; to bow; to curve; to curl\nto lean; to tilt; to incline; to slant\nto bend (the truth); to distort; to twist; to pervert\nto yield (a point); to depart (from a principle); to ignore (what one really thinks)\nto pawn" },
	{ "question": "曲線", "answers": [ "きょくせん" ], "comment": "curve" },
	{ "question": "更ける", "answers": [ "ふける" ], "comment": "to get late; to advance; to wear on" },
	{ "question": "書取", "answers": [ "かきとり" ], "comment": "writing down from other written material; writing kanji text from hiragana\ntranscription (of spoken material)" },
	{ "question": "書店", "answers": [ "しょてん" ], "comment": "bookshop; bookstore" },
	{ "question": "書留", "answers": [ "かきとめ" ], "comment": "registered mail\nregistration (e.g. of mail); writing down; putting on record; recording; making a note of" },
	{ "question": "書籍", "answers": [ "しょせき" ], "comment": "book; publication" },
	{ "question": "書道", "answers": [ "しょどう" ], "comment": "calligraphy" },
	{ "question": "月日", "answers": [ "つきひ" ], "comment": "time; years; days\n(the) date" },
	{ "question": "月末", "answers": [ "げつまつ" ], "comment": "end of the month" },
	{ "question": "月給", "answers": [ "げっきゅう" ], "comment": "monthly salary" },
	{ "question": "有料", "answers": [ "ゆうりょう" ], "comment": "toll; fee; charge; admission-paid" },
	{ "question": "有無", "answers": [ "うむ" ], "comment": "existence or nonexistence; presence or absence\nconsent or refusal; yes or no\nflag indicator; presence or absence marker" },
	{ "question": "有難い", "answers": [ "ありがたい" ], "comment": "grateful; thankful; welcome; appreciated; evoking gratitude" },
	{ "question": "朗らか", "answers": [ "ほがらか" ], "comment": "bright; cheerful; melodious" },
	{ "question": "望遠鏡", "answers": [ "ぼうえんきょう" ], "comment": "telescope" },
	{ "question": "期限", "answers": [ "きげん" ], "comment": "term; period; time frame\ntime limit; deadline; cutoff (date)" },
	{ "question": "木材", "answers": [ "もくざい" ], "comment": "lumber; timber; wood" },
	{ "question": "未満", "answers": [ "みまん" ], "comment": "less than; insufficient" },
	{ "question": "末っ子", "answers": [ "すえっこ" ], "comment": "youngest child" },
	{ "question": "本来", "answers": [ "ほんらい" ], "comment": "originally; primarily\nessentially; naturally; by nature; in (and of) itself\nproper; legal" },
	{ "question": "本棚", "answers": [ "ほんだな" ], "comment": "bookshelves; bookshelf; bookcase" },
	{ "question": "本部", "answers": [ "ほんぶ" ], "comment": "headquarters; head office; main office" },
	{ "question": "杉", "answers": [ "すぎ" ], "comment": "Japanese cedar (Cryptomeria japonica)" },
	{ "question": "材木", "answers": [ "ざいもく" ], "comment": "lumber; timber" },
	{ "question": "来日", "answers": [ "らいにち" ], "comment": "arrival in Japan; coming to Japan; visit to Japan\nfuture day; later date" },
	{ "question": "東洋", "answers": [ "とうよう" ], "comment": "Orient" },
	{ "question": "東西", "answers": [ "とうざい" ], "comment": "east and west\nOrient and Occident; East and West\nLadies and Gentlemen!; Your attention, please!; roll-up, roll-up" },
	{ "question": "枕", "answers": [ "まくら" ], "comment": "pillow; bolster\nintroduction (e.g. to a rakugo story); lead-in" },
	{ "question": "枚数", "answers": [ "まいすう" ], "comment": "the number of flat things\nwin-loss difference which influences the ranking of wrestlers" },
	{ "question": "果して", "answers": [ "はたして" ], "comment": "as was expected; just as one thought; sure enough; as a result\nreally? (in questions); ever?" },
	{ "question": "果実", "answers": [ "かじつ" ], "comment": "fruit; nut; berry" },
	{ "question": "枯れる", "answers": [ "かれる" ], "comment": "to wither (of a plant); to be blasted; to die\nto mature (of one's personality, abilities, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "架空", "answers": [ "かくう" ], "comment": "aerial; overhead\nfictitious; imaginary; fanciful; fabricated" },
	{ "question": "栓", "answers": [ "せん" ], "comment": "stopper; cork; stopcock" },
	{ "question": "校庭", "answers": [ "こうてい" ], "comment": "schoolyard; campus" },
	{ "question": "校舎", "answers": [ "こうしゃ" ], "comment": "school building" },
	{ "question": "格別", "answers": [ "かくべつ" ], "comment": "particular; special; exceptional; especial\nparticularly; especially; exceptionally" },
	{ "question": "桁", "answers": [ "けた" ], "comment": "column; beam; girder; crossbeam; spar; yard\ndigit; decade; order of magnitude" },
	{ "question": "案外", "answers": [ "あんがい" ], "comment": "unexpectedly; surprisingly\nunexpected; unanticipated; unforeseen; surprising" },
	{ "question": "棄てる", "answers": [ "すてる" ], "comment": "to throw away; to cast away; to dump; to discard\nto abandon; to desert; to leave\nto give up; to resign" },
	{ "question": "森林", "answers": [ "しんりん" ], "comment": "forest; woods" },
	{ "question": "植木", "answers": [ "うえき" ], "comment": "garden shrubs; trees; potted plant" },
	{ "question": "楽器", "answers": [ "がっき" ], "comment": "musical instrument" },
	{ "question": "概論", "answers": [ "がいろん" ], "comment": "introduction; outline; general remarks" },
	{ "question": "構造", "answers": [ "こうぞう" ], "comment": "structure; construction; makeup; framework; organization; pattern" },
	{ "question": "標本", "answers": [ "ひょうほん" ], "comment": "example; specimen; sample" },
	{ "question": "標準", "answers": [ "ひょうじゅん" ], "comment": "standard; level; norm" },
	{ "question": "標識", "answers": [ "ひょうしき" ], "comment": "sign; mark; flag" },
	{ "question": "機関車", "answers": [ "きかんしゃ" ], "comment": "locomotive; engine" },
	{ "question": "欄", "answers": [ "らん" ], "comment": "column of text (e.g. in a newspaper)\nfield (in a form, web page, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "次ぐ", "answers": [ "つぐ" ], "comment": "to rank next to; to come after" },
	{ "question": "欧米", "answers": [ "おうべい" ], "comment": "Europe and America; the West" },
	{ "question": "欲張り", "answers": [ "よくばり" ], "comment": "greed; avarice; covetousness; greedy person" },
	{ "question": "歌謡", "answers": [ "かよう" ], "comment": "song; ballad" },
	{ "question": "正味", "answers": [ "しょうみ" ], "comment": "net weight\nuseful part; actual content\nreal; effective; full" },
	{ "question": "正方形", "answers": [ "せいほうけい" ], "comment": "square" },
	{ "question": "正門", "answers": [ "せいもん" ], "comment": "main gate; main entrance" },
	{ "question": "正面", "answers": [ "しょうめん" ], "comment": "front; frontage; facade; main\nthe front\nhonesty; uprightness; directness\ndecency; normality" },
	{ "question": "武士", "answers": [ "ぶし" ], "comment": "warrior; samurai" },
	{ "question": "歯磨き", "answers": [ "はみがき" ], "comment": "dental brushing; brushing one's teeth\ndentifrice; toothpaste; tooth powder" },
	{ "question": "歯車", "answers": [ "はぐるま" ], "comment": "gear; cog-wheel" },
	{ "question": "死体", "answers": [ "したい" ], "comment": "dead body; corpse; cadaver" },
	{ "question": "残らず", "answers": [ "のこらず" ], "comment": "all; entirely; completely; without exception" },
	{ "question": "殖える", "answers": [ "ふえる" ], "comment": "to increase; to multiply" },
	{ "question": "殖やす", "answers": [ "ふやす" ], "comment": "to increase; to add to; to augment" },
	{ "question": "段階", "answers": [ "だんかい" ], "comment": "grade; level; stage; class; phase; steps; order; gradation\nstairs\nstairs at the front of a noh stage" },
	{ "question": "殻", "answers": [ "から" ], "comment": "shell; husk; hull; pod; chaff\nchicken bones (e.g. for soup); chicken carcass\npoor-quality coke (coal)\nleft-overs; remnants\nshell (e.g. electron shell)\negg; eggshell" },
	{ "question": "毎度", "answers": [ "まいど" ], "comment": "each time; always; often\nthank you for your continued patronage" },
	{ "question": "比較的", "answers": [ "ひかくてき" ], "comment": "comparative; relative" },
	{ "question": "毛皮", "answers": [ "けがわ" ], "comment": "fur; skin; pelt\nkanji \"fur\" radical" },
	{ "question": "毛糸", "answers": [ "けいと" ], "comment": "knitting wool; woollen yarn" },
	{ "question": "氏名", "answers": [ "しめい" ], "comment": "full name; identity" },
	{ "question": "民謡", "answers": [ "みんよう" ], "comment": "folk song; popular song" },
	{ "question": "民間", "answers": [ "みんかん" ], "comment": "private; civilian; civil; popular; folk; unofficial" },
	{ "question": "気を付ける", "answers": [ "きをつける" ], "comment": "to be careful; to pay attention; to take care" },
	{ "question": "気体", "answers": [ "きたい" ], "comment": "vapour; vapor; gas" },
	{ "question": "気圧", "answers": [ "きあつ" ], "comment": "atmospheric pressure" },
	{ "question": "気配", "answers": [ "けはい" ], "comment": "indication; sign; hint; presence; trend\nquotation (esp. stock market)" },
	{ "question": "水分", "answers": [ "すいぶん" ], "comment": "water; liquid; fluid; moisture; humidity; sap; juice" },
	{ "question": "水平", "answers": [ "すいへい" ], "comment": "level; horizontality" },
	{ "question": "水平線", "answers": [ "すいへいせん" ], "comment": "horizon (related to sea or lakes)" },
	{ "question": "水曜", "answers": [ "すいよう" ], "comment": "Wednesday" },
	{ "question": "水滴", "answers": [ "すいてき" ], "comment": "drop of water\nvessel for replenishing inkstone water" },
	{ "question": "水産", "answers": [ "すいさん" ], "comment": "aquatic products; fisheries" },
	{ "question": "水筒", "answers": [ "すいとう" ], "comment": "canteen; flask; water bottle; thermos" },
	{ "question": "水素", "answers": [ "すいそ" ], "comment": "hydrogen (H)" },
	{ "question": "水蒸気", "answers": [ "すいじょうき" ], "comment": "water vapour; water vapor; steam" },
	{ "question": "永い", "answers": [ "ながい" ], "comment": "long (time); lengthy" },
	{ "question": "汁", "answers": [ "しる", "つゆ" ], "comment": "juice; sap\nsoup; broth\n(dipping) sauce" },
	{ "question": "汚す", "answers": [ "よごす" ], "comment": "to pollute; to contaminate; to soil; to make dirty; to stain\nto disgrace; to dishonour; to dishonor; to defile" },
	{ "question": "油断", "answers": [ "ゆだん" ], "comment": "negligence; carelessness; inattention; unpreparedness" },
	{ "question": "治す", "answers": [ "なおす" ], "comment": "to cure; to heal\nto fix; to correct; to repair\nto do over again (after -masu base of verb)\nto replace; to put back as it was\nto convert (into a different state); to transform" },
	{ "question": "治める", "answers": [ "おさめる" ], "comment": "to govern; to manage\nto subdue" },
	{ "question": "泊める", "answers": [ "とめる" ], "comment": "to give shelter to; to lodge; to put up; to accommodate" },
	{ "question": "法則", "answers": [ "ほうそく" ], "comment": "law; rule" },
	{ "question": "洋品店", "answers": [ "ようひんてん" ], "comment": "shop that handles Western-style apparel and accessories" },
	{ "question": "洗剤", "answers": [ "せんざい" ], "comment": "detergent; washing material" },
	{ "question": "活力", "answers": [ "かつりょく" ], "comment": "vitality; energy; dynamism" },
	{ "question": "活字", "answers": [ "かつじ" ], "comment": "printing type; movable type\nprinted text; print" },
	{ "question": "活躍", "answers": [ "かつやく" ], "comment": "activity (esp. energetic); great efforts; conspicuous service\nto flourish; to participate actively; to play an active role" },
	{ "question": "派手", "answers": [ "はで" ], "comment": "showy; loud; gay; flashy; gaudy" },
	{ "question": "流域", "answers": [ "りゅういき" ], "comment": "(river) basin" },
	{ "question": "流石", "answers": [ "さすが" ], "comment": "as one would expect\nstill; all the same\neven... (e.g. \"even a genius...\")" },
	{ "question": "流行る", "answers": [ "はやる" ], "comment": "to be popular; to come into fashion\nto be prevalent; to spread widely (e.g. disease); to be endemic\nto flourish; to thrive" },
	{ "question": "浮かべる", "answers": [ "うかべる" ], "comment": "to float; to set afloat; to launch\nto show on one's face (smile, sadness, etc.)\nto recall; to call to mind; to imagine; to think of" },
	{ "question": "浮く", "answers": [ "うく" ], "comment": "to float\nto become merry; to be cheerful\nto become loose; to become unsteady\nto feel out of it; to be cut off (e.g. from those around you); to feel out of place\nto be frivolous; to be uncertain\nto have (time, money, etc.) left over; to be saved (e.g. money)\nto have no basis; to be unreliable" },
	{ "question": "浮ぶ", "answers": [ "うかぶ" ], "comment": "to float; to be suspended\nto rise to surface\nto come to mind; to have inspiration" },
	{ "question": "浴衣", "answers": [ "ゆかた" ], "comment": "yukata (light cotton kimono worn in the summer or used as a bathrobe)" },
	{ "question": "海水浴", "answers": [ "かいすいよく" ], "comment": "swimming in the ocean; sea bathing; seawater bath; going for a dip in the ocean" },
	{ "question": "海洋", "answers": [ "かいよう" ], "comment": "ocean" },
	{ "question": "浸ける", "answers": [ "つける" ], "comment": "to soak; to seep; to dip in" },
	{ "question": "消化", "answers": [ "しょうか" ], "comment": "digestion\nthorough understanding\nselling accumulated (excess) products; dealing with a large amount of work\nlosing one's form and turning into something else" },
	{ "question": "消極的", "answers": [ "しょうきょくてき" ], "comment": "negative; passive; half-hearted; unmotivated" },
	{ "question": "消毒", "answers": [ "しょうどく" ], "comment": "disinfection; sterilization; sterilisation" },
	{ "question": "消耗", "answers": [ "しょうもう" ], "comment": "exhaustion; consumption; waste; dissipation" },
	{ "question": "消防署", "answers": [ "しょうぼうしょ" ], "comment": "fire station" },
	{ "question": "液体", "answers": [ "えきたい" ], "comment": "liquid; fluid" },
	{ "question": "涼む", "answers": [ "すずむ" ], "comment": "to cool oneself; to cool off; to enjoy the cool air" },
	{ "question": "淡水", "answers": [ "たんすい" ], "comment": "fresh water (i.e. not salt water)" },
	{ "question": "深まる", "answers": [ "ふかまる" ], "comment": "to deepen; to heighten; to intensify" },
	{ "question": "深夜", "answers": [ "しんや" ], "comment": "late at night" },
	{ "question": "混ざる", "answers": [ "まざる" ], "comment": "to be mixed; to be blended with; to associate with; to mingle with; to join" },
	{ "question": "混じる", "answers": [ "まじる" ], "comment": "to be mixed; to be blended with; to associate with; to mingle with; to interest; to join\nto be mixed in with; to blend with" },
	{ "question": "混ぜる", "answers": [ "まぜる" ], "comment": "to mix; to stir; to blend" },
	{ "question": "混合", "answers": [ "こんごう" ], "comment": "mixing; mixture; meld\nmiscegenation" },
	{ "question": "清い", "answers": [ "きよい" ], "comment": "clear; pure; noble" },
	{ "question": "清む", "answers": [ "すむ" ], "comment": "to clear (e.g. weather); to become transparent" },
	{ "question": "清掃", "answers": [ "せいそう" ], "comment": "cleaning; clean-up; garbage collection; scavenging" },
	{ "question": "清書", "answers": [ "せいしょ" ], "comment": "clean copy" },
	{ "question": "渇く", "answers": [ "かわく" ], "comment": "to be thirsty; to feel thirsty\nto thirst for; to crave" },
	{ "question": "温室", "answers": [ "おんしつ" ], "comment": "greenhouse; hothouse; conservatory; glasshouse" },
	{ "question": "温帯", "answers": [ "おんたい" ], "comment": "temperate zone" },
	{ "question": "温泉", "answers": [ "おんせん" ], "comment": "spa; hot spring; onsen" },
	{ "question": "測る", "answers": [ "はかる" ], "comment": "to measure; to weigh; to survey; to time (sound, gauge, estimate)\nto conjecture; to infer; to surmise" },
	{ "question": "測定", "answers": [ "そくてい" ], "comment": "measurement" },
	{ "question": "測量", "answers": [ "そくりょう" ], "comment": "measurement; surveying" },
	{ "question": "湧く", "answers": [ "わく" ], "comment": "to well (up); to gush forth (of water); to spring out; to surge\nto appear (esp. suddenly) (sweat, tears, etc.)\nto feel emotions form (joy, bravery, etc.)\nto hatch (esp. of parasitic insects, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "湯気", "answers": [ "ゆげ" ], "comment": "steam; vapour; vapor" },
	{ "question": "湯飲み", "answers": [ "ゆのみ" ], "comment": "teacup" },
	{ "question": "湿る", "answers": [ "しめる" ], "comment": "to be wet; to become wet; to be damp; to be moist\nto be in low spirits; to feel depressed" },
	{ "question": "湿度", "answers": [ "しつど" ], "comment": "level of humidity" },
	{ "question": "湿気", "answers": [ "しっけ" ], "comment": "moisture; humidity; dampness" },
	{ "question": "満員", "answers": [ "まんいん" ], "comment": "full house; no vacancy; sold out; standing room only; full (of people); crowded" },
	{ "question": "満点", "answers": [ "まんてん" ], "comment": "perfect score; full marks\nextremely; very; quite" },
	{ "question": "溶かす", "answers": [ "とかす" ], "comment": "to melt; to dissolve" },
	{ "question": "溶く", "answers": [ "とく" ], "comment": "to dissolve (paint); to scramble (eggs); to melt (metal, etc.); to mix (water with flour, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "溶ける", "answers": [ "とける" ], "comment": "to melt; to thaw; to fuse; to dissolve" },
	{ "question": "溶け込む", "answers": [ "とけこむ" ], "comment": "to melt into; to merge into\nto fit in; to adapt; to blend" },
	{ "question": "溶岩", "answers": [ "ようがん" ], "comment": "lava" },
	{ "question": "滑れる", "answers": [ "ずれる" ] },
	{ "question": "滝", "answers": [ "たき" ], "comment": "waterfall\nrapids" },
	{ "question": "漁師", "answers": [ "りょうし" ], "comment": "fisherman" },
	{ "question": "漁業", "answers": [ "ぎょぎょう" ], "comment": "fishing (industry)" },
	{ "question": "演劇", "answers": [ "えんげき" ], "comment": "drama; theatre; theater; play" },
	{ "question": "漢和", "answers": [ "かんわ" ], "comment": "China and Japan\nChinese and Japanese (languages)\nChinese Character-Japanese dictionary" },
	{ "question": "潜る", "answers": [ "もぐる" ], "comment": "to go under; to pass under; to go through; to pass through\nto dive (into or under the water)\nto evade; to get around; to slip past\nto survive; to surmount\nto dive (into or under water)\nto get under; to get into; to get in; to creep into; to crawl under; to bury oneself; to burrow into; to dig oneself into; to snuggle under\nto hide oneself (esp. from the government); to conceal oneself; to go underground" },
	{ "question": "潰す", "answers": [ "つぶす" ], "comment": "to smash; to crush\nto shut down\nto thwart; to block\nto kill (time)\nto waste (e.g. talents)" },
	{ "question": "潰れる", "answers": [ "つぶれる" ], "comment": "to be crushed; to be smashed; to be broken; to collapse\nto become useless; to cease functioning; to be wasted (e.g. time)\nto go bankrupt; to go out of business; to fail" },
	{ "question": "澄む", "answers": [ "すむ" ], "comment": "to clear (e.g. weather); to become transparent" },
	{ "question": "激増", "answers": [ "げきぞう" ], "comment": "sudden increase" },
	{ "question": "濁る", "answers": [ "にごる" ], "comment": "to become muddy; to become cloudy; to get impure (of a liquid, gas, etc.)\nto become dull (of a sound, color, etc.); to become hoarse\nto become impure (of a heart, society, etc.); to be corrupted; to be polluted\nto become voiced; to add voiced consonant marks" },
	{ "question": "濃度", "answers": [ "のうど" ], "comment": "concentration; thickness; density\ncardinality" },
	{ "question": "瀬戸物", "answers": [ "せともの" ], "comment": "earthenware; porcelain; china; pottery; crockery" },
	{ "question": "火傷", "answers": [ "やけど" ], "comment": "burn; scald" },
	{ "question": "火口", "answers": [ "かこう" ], "comment": "crater; caldera\nburner (e.g. on a furnace)\nburner; nozzle; origin of a fire\ntinder; touchwood; charcloth" },
	{ "question": "火山", "answers": [ "かざん" ], "comment": "volcano" },
	{ "question": "灯台", "answers": [ "とうだい" ], "comment": "lighthouse\nold-fashioned interior light fixture comprising a wooden pole with an oil-filled dish and a wick atop it" },
	{ "question": "灯油", "answers": [ "とうゆ" ], "comment": "lamp oil; kerosene" },
	{ "question": "灰色", "answers": [ "はいいろ" ], "comment": "grey; gray; ashen" },
	{ "question": "災難", "answers": [ "さいなん" ], "comment": "calamity; misfortune; disaster" },
	{ "question": "炊く", "answers": [ "たく" ], "comment": "to cook (grains, e.g. rice)\nto boil; to simmer; to stew; to seethe" },
	{ "question": "炊事", "answers": [ "すいじ" ], "comment": "cooking; culinary arts" },
	{ "question": "炭鉱", "answers": [ "たんこう" ], "comment": "coal mine; coal pit" },
	{ "question": "点々", "answers": [ "てんてん" ], "comment": "here and there; little by little; sporadically; scattered in drops\ndots; spots" },
	{ "question": "点く", "answers": [ "つく" ], "comment": "to be lit (e.g. electricity comes on); to be lighted\nto catch fire" },
	{ "question": "点ける", "answers": [ "つける" ], "comment": "to turn on; to switch on; to light up" },
	{ "question": "点数", "answers": [ "てんすう" ], "comment": "marks; points; score; runs; number of items; credits" },
	{ "question": "為す", "answers": [ "なす" ], "comment": "to build up; to establish\nto form; to become (a state)\nto accomplish; to achieve; to succeed in\nto change into\nto do; to perform\nto intend to; to attempt; to try" },
	{ "question": "為替", "answers": [ "かわせ" ], "comment": "money order; draft\nexchange (e.g. foreign)" },
	{ "question": "無地", "answers": [ "むじ" ], "comment": "plain; unfigured" },
	{ "question": "無数", "answers": [ "むすう" ], "comment": "countless number; infinite number; innumerable" },
	{ "question": "無沙汰", "answers": [ "ぶさた" ], "comment": "not writing or contacting for a while; neglecting to write (call, visit, etc.); failing to write (call, visit, etc.); long silence" },
	{ "question": "無限", "answers": [ "むげん" ], "comment": "infinity; infinitude; eternity\ninfinite; limitless" },
	{ "question": "焦がす", "answers": [ "こがす" ], "comment": "to burn; to scorch; to singe; to char" },
	{ "question": "焦げる", "answers": [ "こげる" ], "comment": "to burn; to scorch; to char; to singe" },
	{ "question": "焦点", "answers": [ "しょうてん" ], "comment": "focus (e.g. photographic); focal point" },
	{ "question": "煎る", "answers": [ "いる" ], "comment": "to parch; to fry; to fire; to broil; to roast; to boil down (in oil)" },
	{ "question": "煙い", "answers": [ "けむい" ], "comment": "smoky" },
	{ "question": "煙突", "answers": [ "えんとつ" ], "comment": "chimney; smokestack; funnel (of a ship); stovepipe\ncarrying a passenger without turning on the taximeter" },
	{ "question": "照らす", "answers": [ "てらす" ], "comment": "to shine on; to illuminate\nto compare (with); to refer to" },
	{ "question": "照る", "answers": [ "てる" ], "comment": "to shine\nto look slightly upward (of a noh mask; indicating joy, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "煮える", "answers": [ "にえる" ], "comment": "to be boiled; to be cooked" },
	{ "question": "煮る", "answers": [ "にる" ], "comment": "to boil; to simmer; to stew; to seethe" },
	{ "question": "熟語", "answers": [ "じゅくご" ], "comment": "kanji compound\nidiom; idiomatic phrase" },
	{ "question": "熱する", "answers": [ "ねっする" ], "comment": "to heat; to heat up" },
	{ "question": "燃やす", "answers": [ "もやす" ], "comment": "to burn" },
	{ "question": "爪", "answers": [ "つめ" ], "comment": "nail (e.g. fingernail, toenail); claw; talon; hoof\nplectrum; pick\nhook; clasp" },
	{ "question": "父母", "answers": [ "ふぼ" ], "comment": "father and mother; parents" },
	{ "question": "片付く", "answers": [ "かたづく" ], "comment": "to be put in order; to be put to rights\nto be disposed of; to be solved\nto be finished\nto be married (off)" },
	{ "question": "片仮名", "answers": [ "かたかな" ], "comment": "katakana; angular Japanese syllabary used primarily for loanwords" },
	{ "question": "片寄る", "answers": [ "かたよる" ], "comment": "to be one-sided; to incline; to be partial; to be prejudiced; to lean; to be biased; to be biassed" },
	{ "question": "片道", "answers": [ "かたみち" ], "comment": "one-way (trip)\none-way ticket" },
	{ "question": "牧場", "answers": [ "ぼくじょう" ], "comment": "farm (livestock); ranch (US); station (Aus, NZ)\npasture land; meadow; grazing land" },
	{ "question": "牧畜", "answers": [ "ぼくちく" ], "comment": "stock-farming" },
	{ "question": "物凄い", "answers": [ "ものすごい" ], "comment": "earth-shattering; staggering; to a very great extent\nterrible; frightful; horrible; ghastly" },
	{ "question": "物差し", "answers": [ "ものさし" ], "comment": "ruler; measure" },
	{ "question": "物置", "answers": [ "ものおき" ], "comment": "storage room; storeroom; lumber room" },
	{ "question": "物語る", "answers": [ "ものがたる" ], "comment": "to tell; to indicate" },
	{ "question": "物騒", "answers": [ "ぶっそう" ], "comment": "dangerous; unsettled; troubled; disturbed; insecure" },
	{ "question": "特売", "answers": [ "とくばい" ], "comment": "special sale" },
	{ "question": "特定", "answers": [ "とくてい" ], "comment": "specific; particular; designated; special\nspecifying; designating; identifying; pinpointing" },
	{ "question": "特殊", "answers": [ "とくしゅ" ], "comment": "special; particular; peculiar; unique" },
	{ "question": "特色", "answers": [ "とくしょく" ], "comment": "characteristic; feature; idiosyncrasy; personal colour\nspot color (in printing)" },
	{ "question": "特長", "answers": [ "とくちょう" ], "comment": "forte; merit" },
	{ "question": "狙い", "answers": [ "ねらい" ], "comment": "aim" },
	{ "question": "狙う", "answers": [ "ねらう" ], "comment": "to aim at" },
	{ "question": "独り言", "answers": [ "ひとりごと" ], "comment": "soliloquy; monologue; speaking to oneself" },
	{ "question": "献立", "answers": [ "こんだて" ], "comment": "menu; bill of fare\nprogram; programme; schedule" },
	{ "question": "率直", "answers": [ "そっちょく" ], "comment": "frankness; candour; candor; openheartedness; directness" },
	{ "question": "王女", "answers": [ "おうじょ" ], "comment": "princess" },
	{ "question": "現に", "answers": [ "げんに" ], "comment": "actually; really" },
	{ "question": "理科", "answers": [ "りか" ], "comment": "science" },
	{ "question": "琴", "answers": [ "こと", "きん" ], "comment": "koto (13-stringed Japanese zither)\nstringed instrument\nqin (7-stringed Chinese zither); guqin" },
	{ "question": "瓦", "answers": [ "かわら" ], "comment": "gram; gramme\nroof tile" },
	{ "question": "瓶詰め", "answers": [ "びんづめ" ], "comment": "bottling; bottled" },
	{ "question": "甘やかす", "answers": [ "あまやかす" ], "comment": "to pamper; to spoil" },
	{ "question": "甚だしい", "answers": [ "はなはだしい" ], "comment": "extreme; excessive; terrible; intense; severe; serious; tremendous; heavy (damage)" },
	{ "question": "生える", "answers": [ "はえる" ], "comment": "to grow; to spring up; to sprout\nto cut (teeth)" },
	{ "question": "生き生き", "answers": [ "いきいき" ], "comment": "vividly; lively" },
	{ "question": "生け花", "answers": [ "いけばな" ], "comment": "ikebana; Japanese art of flower arrangement\nfresh flower; natural flower" },
	{ "question": "生ずる", "answers": [ "しょうずる" ], "comment": "to produce; to yield; to cause\nto result from; to arise; to be generated" },
	{ "question": "生存", "answers": [ "せいぞん" ], "comment": "existence; being; survival\nto exist; to live; to survive" },
	{ "question": "生年月日", "answers": [ "せいねんがっぴ" ], "comment": "birth date; date of birth; DOB" },
	{ "question": "生意気", "answers": [ "なまいき" ], "comment": "impertinent; saucy; cheeky; conceit; audacious; brazen; feisty" },
	{ "question": "生長", "answers": [ "せいちょう" ], "comment": "growth; increment" },
	{ "question": "産地", "answers": [ "さんち" ], "comment": "producing area" },
	{ "question": "用語", "answers": [ "ようご" ], "comment": "term; terminology\nwording; choice of words; phraseology" },
	{ "question": "用途", "answers": [ "ようと" ], "comment": "use; usefulness; utility; service; purpose" },
	{ "question": "田んぼ", "answers": [ "たんぼ" ], "comment": "paddy field; farm" },
	{ "question": "田植え", "answers": [ "たうえ" ], "comment": "rice planting" },
	{ "question": "申し訳ない", "answers": [ "もうしわけない" ], "comment": "I'm sorry; (it's) inexcusable; I feel regretful; I feel guilty\nthank you very much (for help, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "申請", "answers": [ "しんせい" ], "comment": "application; request; petition" },
	{ "question": "留まる", "answers": [ "とどまる" ], "comment": "to stop (moving); to come to a stop\nto stop (doing, working, being supplied); to come to a halt; to cease; to be stopped; to be suspended\nto alight; to perch on\nto remain; to abide; to stay (in the one place)\nto be limited to; to be confined to" },
	{ "question": "留守番", "answers": [ "るすばん" ], "comment": "care-taking; house-sitting; house-watching; staying at home\ncaretaker; house-sitter" },
	{ "question": "略す", "answers": [ "りゃくす" ], "comment": "to abbreviate; to omit\nto take; to capture" },
	{ "question": "番地", "answers": [ "ばんち" ], "comment": "house number; address" },
	{ "question": "畳む", "answers": [ "たたむ" ], "comment": "to fold (clothes, umbrella)\nto close (a shop, business)\nto vacate" },
	{ "question": "発つ", "answers": [ "たつ" ], "comment": "to depart (on a plane, train, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "発売", "answers": [ "はつばい" ], "comment": "sale; offering for sale; release (for sale); launch (product)" },
	{ "question": "発射", "answers": [ "はっしゃ" ], "comment": "firing; shooting; discharge; catapult\nejaculation" },
	{ "question": "発想", "answers": [ "はっそう" ], "comment": "idea; conception; way of thinking\nexpression" },
	{ "question": "発揮", "answers": [ "はっき" ], "comment": "exhibition; demonstration; show; display; manifestation" },
	{ "question": "発電", "answers": [ "はつでん" ], "comment": "generation (e.g. power)\nsending a telegram; telegraphing" },
	{ "question": "登場", "answers": [ "とうじょう" ], "comment": "entry (on stage); appearance (on screen)\nentrance; introduction (into a market)" },
	{ "question": "白髪", "answers": [ "しらが" ], "comment": "white hair; grey hair; gray hair" },
	{ "question": "的確", "answers": [ "てきかく" ], "comment": "precise; accurate; appropriate; exactly the right" },
	{ "question": "皮肉", "answers": [ "ひにく" ], "comment": "cynicism; sarcasm; irony; satire" },
	{ "question": "皮膚", "answers": [ "ひふ" ], "comment": "skin" },
	{ "question": "盆", "answers": [ "ぼん" ], "comment": "tray\nfamily; household\nO-Bon; Bon Festival; Lantern Festival; Festival of the Dead" },
	{ "question": "盆地", "answers": [ "ぼんち" ], "comment": "basin (e.g. between mountains)" },
	{ "question": "盗難", "answers": [ "とうなん" ], "comment": "theft; robbery" },
	{ "question": "盛る", "answers": [ "もる" ], "comment": "to prosper; to flourish\nto copulate (animals)\nto serve (food, etc.); to dish out\nto fill up; to pile up; to heap\nto prescribe; to administer; to dose out\nto put into (e.g. information in a report)\nto mark out (e.g. scale); to graduate (e.g. thermometer)\nto exaggerate; to apply heavy makeup" },
	{ "question": "目上", "answers": [ "めうえ" ], "comment": "superior; superiors; senior" },
	{ "question": "目下", "answers": [ "めした" ], "comment": "subordinate; subordinates; inferior; inferiors; junior\nat present; now" },
	{ "question": "目印", "answers": [ "めじるし" ], "comment": "mark; sign; landmark; benchmark" },
	{ "question": "目安", "answers": [ "めやす" ], "comment": "criterion; standard; yardstick; reference; aim\nrough estimate; approximation" },
	{ "question": "目指す", "answers": [ "めざす" ], "comment": "to aim at; to have an eye on\nto go toward; to head for" },
	{ "question": "目次", "answers": [ "もくじ" ], "comment": "table of contents" },
	{ "question": "目立つ", "answers": [ "めだつ" ], "comment": "to be conspicuous; to stand out" },
	{ "question": "目覚し", "answers": [ "めざまし" ], "comment": "alarm clock\nopening one's eyes; keeping one's eyes open\ntype of candy given to a child after it wakes up from a nap" },
	{ "question": "直前", "answers": [ "ちょくぜん" ], "comment": "just before" },
	{ "question": "直径", "answers": [ "ちょっけい" ], "comment": "diameter" },
	{ "question": "直後", "answers": [ "ちょくご" ], "comment": "immediately following" },
	{ "question": "直流", "answers": [ "ちょくりゅう" ], "comment": "direct current; DC" },
	{ "question": "直線", "answers": [ "ちょくせん" ], "comment": "straight line" },
	{ "question": "直角", "answers": [ "ちょっかく" ], "comment": "right angle; perpendicular" },
	{ "question": "直通", "answers": [ "ちょくつう" ], "comment": "direct line; direct communication; connecting directly; through service" },
	{ "question": "相互", "answers": [ "そうご" ], "comment": "mutual; reciprocal" },
	{ "question": "相撲", "answers": [ "すもう" ], "comment": "sumo wrestling\nwrestler; rikishi" },
	{ "question": "相違", "answers": [ "そうい" ], "comment": "difference; discrepancy; variation" },
	{ "question": "省略", "answers": [ "しょうりゃく" ], "comment": "omission; abbreviation; abridgment; abridgement" },
	{ "question": "看板", "answers": [ "かんばん" ], "comment": "signboard; sign; billboard; hoarding; doorplate\ndraw; attraction; feature; highlight; spokesman; figurehead\nreputation (of a shop)\nappearance; look\nclosing time" },
	{ "question": "看病", "answers": [ "かんびょう" ], "comment": "nursing (a patient)" },
	{ "question": "県庁", "answers": [ "けんちょう" ], "comment": "prefectural office" },
	{ "question": "真っ先", "answers": [ "まっさき" ], "comment": "the head; the foremost; beginning; the very front" },
	{ "question": "真っ暗", "answers": [ "まっくら" ], "comment": "total darkness; pitch dark\nbleak future; poor prospects" },
	{ "question": "真っ白", "answers": [ "まっしろ" ], "comment": "pure white\nblank (e.g. mind, paper)" },
	{ "question": "真っ青", "answers": [ "まっさお" ], "comment": "deep blue; bright blue\nghastly pale; pallid; white as a sheet" },
	{ "question": "真っ黒", "answers": [ "まっくろ" ], "comment": "pitch black" },
	{ "question": "真似る", "answers": [ "まねる" ], "comment": "to mimic; to imitate" },
	{ "question": "真空", "answers": [ "しんくう" ], "comment": "vacuum; hollow; empty" },
	{ "question": "着々", "answers": [ "ちゃくちゃく" ], "comment": "steadily" },
	{ "question": "着ける", "answers": [ "つける" ], "comment": "to attach; to join; to add; to append; to affix; to stick; to glue; to fasten; to sew on; to apply (ointment)\nto furnish (a house with)\nto wear; to put on\nto keep a diary; to make an entry\nto appraise; to set (a price)\nto allot; to budget; to assign\nto bring alongside\nto place (under guard or doctor)\nto follow; to shadow\nto load; to give (courage to)\nto keep (an eye on)\nto establish (relations or understanding)\nto turn on (light)\nto produce flowers; to produce fruit" },
	{ "question": "着せる", "answers": [ "きせる" ], "comment": "to put clothes on (someone)\nto plate; to gild; to veneer\nto accuse (of some crime); to give (a bad name)" },
	{ "question": "着替え", "answers": [ "きがえ" ], "comment": "changing clothes; change of clothes" },
	{ "question": "瞳", "answers": [ "ひとみ" ], "comment": "pupil (of eye)\neye" },
	{ "question": "矛盾", "answers": [ "むじゅん" ], "comment": "contradiction; inconsistency" },
	{ "question": "矢印", "answers": [ "やじるし" ], "comment": "arrow (mark or symbol); directional marker or indicator" },
	{ "question": "知人", "answers": [ "ちじん" ], "comment": "friend; acquaintance" },
	{ "question": "知合い", "answers": [ "しりあい" ], "comment": "acquaintance" },
	{ "question": "短所", "answers": [ "たんしょ" ], "comment": "defect; demerit; weak point; disadvantage" },
	{ "question": "短期", "answers": [ "たんき" ], "comment": "short-term" },
	{ "question": "短編", "answers": [ "たんぺん" ], "comment": "short (e.g. story, film)" },
	{ "question": "砂糖", "answers": [ "さとう" ], "comment": "sugar" },
	{ "question": "研修", "answers": [ "けんしゅう" ], "comment": "training (esp. in-service); induction course" },
	{ "question": "砕く", "answers": [ "くだく" ], "comment": "to break; to smash" },
	{ "question": "砕ける", "answers": [ "くだける" ], "comment": "to break (into pieces); to be broken; to be smashed\nto collapse; to crumble; to decline; to cool (e.g. enthusiasm); to dampen (e.g. one's will to fight)\nto become less formal; to throw off reserve; to become affable\nto become easy to understand (e.g. a story)\nto be worried" },
	{ "question": "破く", "answers": [ "やぶく" ], "comment": "to tear; to violate; to defeat; to smash; to destroy" },
	{ "question": "破れる", "answers": [ "やぶれる" ], "comment": "to break; to be smashed\nto split; to crack; to fissure; to be torn\nto be divided; to cleave\nto come to light; to be identified; to be established; to become clear\nto get torn; to tear; to rip; to break; to wear out\nto be broken off (of negotiations, etc.); to break down; to collapse; to fall into ruin" },
	{ "question": "破片", "answers": [ "はへん" ], "comment": "fragment; broken piece; splinter; chip; shard" },
	{ "question": "碁", "answers": [ "ご" ], "comment": "go (board game of capturing territory)" },
	{ "question": "確率", "answers": [ "かくりつ" ], "comment": "probability; likelihood; chances" },
	{ "question": "磁石", "answers": [ "じしゃく" ], "comment": "magnet\ncompass" },
	{ "question": "磨く", "answers": [ "みがく" ], "comment": "to polish; to shine; to brush (e.g. teeth)\nto refine; to improve" },
	{ "question": "社会科学", "answers": [ "しゃかいかがく" ], "comment": "social science" },
	{ "question": "社説", "answers": [ "しゃせつ" ], "comment": "editorial; leading article" },
	{ "question": "祖先", "answers": [ "そせん" ], "comment": "ancestor" },
	{ "question": "祝日", "answers": [ "しゅくじつ" ], "comment": "national holiday; public holiday" },
	{ "question": "神様", "answers": [ "かみさま" ], "comment": "God" },
	{ "question": "神話", "answers": [ "しんわ" ], "comment": "myth; legend" },
	{ "question": "祭る", "answers": [ "まつる" ], "comment": "to deify; to enshrine\nto pray; to worship" },
	{ "question": "祭日", "answers": [ "さいじつ" ], "comment": "national holiday; festival day" },
	{ "question": "私立", "answers": [ "しりつ" ], "comment": "private (establishment)" },
	{ "question": "私鉄", "answers": [ "してつ" ], "comment": "private railway" },
	{ "question": "移転", "answers": [ "いてん" ], "comment": "moving; relocation; change of address\ntransfer (of deeds, property, etc.); demise" },
	{ "question": "税関", "answers": [ "ぜいかん" ], "comment": "customs; customs house" },
	{ "question": "稽古", "answers": [ "けいこ" ], "comment": "practice; practising; training; study" },
	{ "question": "積む", "answers": [ "つむ" ], "comment": "to pile up; to stack\nto load (car, ship, etc.); to pack\nto acquire; to accumulate" },
	{ "question": "空っぽ", "answers": [ "からっぽ" ], "comment": "empty; vacant; hollow" },
	{ "question": "空中", "answers": [ "くうちゅう" ], "comment": "sky; air" },
	{ "question": "空想", "answers": [ "くうそう" ], "comment": "daydream; fantasy; fancy; vision" },
	{ "question": "突き当たり", "answers": [ "つきあたり" ], "comment": "end (e.g. of street, hallway, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "突き当たる", "answers": [ "つきあたる" ], "comment": "to run into; to collide with; to crash into; to bump against\nto come to the end of (a street)\nto run into (difficulties, problems, etc.); to run up against" },
	{ "question": "突く", "answers": [ "つく" ], "comment": "to prick; to stab\nto poke; to prod; to push; to thrust; to nudge; to hit; to strike\nto use (a cane); to prop oneself up with; to press against (the floor, etc.)\nto attack\nto brave (the rain, etc.)\nto poke (repeatedly, lightly); to nudge\nto peck at (one's food); to pick at\nto peck at (someone's faults, etc.)\nto egg on; to put up to" },
	{ "question": "突っ込む", "answers": [ "つっこむ" ], "comment": "to thrust (something) into (something); to cram\nto plunge into; to go into deeply\nto get involved with; to meddle; to poke one's nose into\nto riposte; to retort; to quip" },
	{ "question": "窓口", "answers": [ "まどぐち" ], "comment": "ticket window; teller window; counter\ncontact person; point of contact" },
	{ "question": "立ち止まる", "answers": [ "たちどまる" ], "comment": "to stop; to halt; to stand still" },
	{ "question": "童話", "answers": [ "どうわ" ], "comment": "fairy-tale" },
	{ "question": "競馬", "answers": [ "けいば" ], "comment": "horse racing\ntraditional horse-racing; originally two horses head-to-head or ten at a time, esp. May 5th event at Kamigamo shrine" },
	{ "question": "竹", "answers": [ "たけ" ], "comment": "bamboo\nmiddle (of a three-tier ranking system)" },
	{ "question": "符号", "answers": [ "ふごう" ], "comment": "sign; mark; symbol; code\nsign (e.g. positive, negative)" },
	{ "question": "筆者", "answers": [ "ひっしゃ" ], "comment": "writer (often in self-reference); author" },
	{ "question": "筆記", "answers": [ "ひっき" ], "comment": "(taking) notes; copying" },
	{ "question": "等分", "answers": [ "とうぶん" ], "comment": "division into equal parts" },
	{ "question": "算数", "answers": [ "さんすう" ], "comment": "arithmetic" },
	{ "question": "箸", "answers": [ "はし" ], "comment": "chopsticks" },
	{ "question": "粒", "answers": [ "つぶ" ], "comment": "grain; bead; drop\ncounter for small round objects including grains, seeds, pills, drops" },
	{ "question": "系統", "answers": [ "けいとう" ], "comment": "system\nlineage; ancestry; family line\ngroup (e.g. of colors) (colours); family (e.g. of languages); party; school (of thought)\nclose (evolutionary) relationship\na population sharing a common ancestor (in genetics); strain (e.g. bacterial)" },
	{ "question": "紅葉", "answers": [ "もみじ" ], "comment": "autumn colours; fall colors; leaves changing color (colour)\nleaves turning red; red leaves\n(Japanese) maple (Acer japonicum)\nvenison" },
	{ "question": "納める", "answers": [ "おさめる" ], "comment": "to dedicate; to make an offering; to pay (fees)\nto supply\nto store\nto finish; to bring to a close\nto restore (something to its place)\nto achieve (e.g. a result)" },
	{ "question": "純情", "answers": [ "じゅんじょう" ], "comment": "pure heart; naivete; innocence" },
	{ "question": "純粋", "answers": [ "じゅんすい" ], "comment": "pure; true; genuine; unmixed" },
	{ "question": "紙幣", "answers": [ "しへい" ], "comment": "paper money; note; bill" },
	{ "question": "素人", "answers": [ "しろうと" ], "comment": "amateur; layman; ordinary person; novice\nrespectable woman (not a prostitute, hostess, geisha, etc.)\nunlicensed prostitute" },
	{ "question": "素直", "answers": [ "すなお" ], "comment": "obedient; meek; docile; unaffected\nhonest; frank; upfront (about one's feelings)" },
	{ "question": "素質", "answers": [ "そしつ" ], "comment": "character; qualities; genius; the makings of" },
	{ "question": "索引", "answers": [ "さくいん" ], "comment": "index; indices; indexes" },
	{ "question": "紫", "answers": [ "むらさき" ], "comment": "purple; violet\nLithospermum erythrorhizon (species of gromwell)\ntype of soy sauce" },
	{ "question": "紺", "answers": [ "こん" ], "comment": "navy blue; deep blue" },
	{ "question": "終了", "answers": [ "しゅうりょう" ], "comment": "end; close; termination" },
	{ "question": "終点", "answers": [ "しゅうてん" ], "comment": "terminus; last stop (e.g. train)" },
	{ "question": "組み立てる", "answers": [ "くみたてる" ], "comment": "to assemble; to set up; to construct" },
	{ "question": "組合せ", "answers": [ "くみあわせ" ], "comment": "combination" },
	{ "question": "経度", "answers": [ "けいど" ], "comment": "longitude" },
	{ "question": "絞る", "answers": [ "しぼる" ], "comment": "to wring (towel, rag); to squeeze\nto squeeze (fruit to extract juice); to press; to extract; to milk; to express milk\nto rack (one's brains); to strain (one's voice)\nto extort; to exploit\nto chew out; to reprimand severely; to rake over the coals; to give a sound scolding; to tell someone off; to scold; to rebuke\nto drill into; to train\nto narrow down (one's focus); to whittle down\nto gather up (curtain, etc.); to tighten (drawstring)\nto stop down (lens)\nto turn down (e.g. radio)\nto bend (bow); to draw\nto hold down; to constrict; to immobilize" },
	{ "question": "給与", "answers": [ "きゅうよ" ], "comment": "pay; salary; wages; allowance; grant; supply" },
	{ "question": "統一", "answers": [ "とういつ" ], "comment": "unity; consolidation; uniformity; unification; compatible" },
	{ "question": "統計", "answers": [ "とうけい" ], "comment": "statistics" },
	{ "question": "絵の具", "answers": [ "えのぐ" ], "comment": "paint; coloring materials; colors; colours" },
	{ "question": "絶えず", "answers": [ "たえず" ], "comment": "constantly; always; continually; steadily" },
	{ "question": "継続", "answers": [ "けいぞく" ], "comment": "continuation" },
	{ "question": "続々", "answers": [ "ぞくぞく" ], "comment": "successively; one after another" },
	{ "question": "綱", "answers": [ "つな" ], "comment": "rope\ngrand champion's braided belt\nclass" },
	{ "question": "総理大臣", "answers": [ "そうりだいじん" ], "comment": "prime minister (as the head of a cabinet government); premier" },
	{ "question": "線路", "answers": [ "せんろ" ], "comment": "railway track; railway line; railroad; railway; track; line" },
	{ "question": "締め切る", "answers": [ "しめきる" ], "comment": "to close up; to shut up (e.g. behind doors)\nto cut off (e.g. because a deadline has expired); to close off (e.g. subscription list)" },
	{ "question": "締切", "answers": [ "しめきり" ], "comment": "deadline; closing; cut-off; end\ncofferdam\nclosed (door, window, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "編む", "answers": [ "あむ" ], "comment": "to knit; to plait; to braid\nto compile (anthology, dictionary, etc.); to edit" },
	{ "question": "編物", "answers": [ "あみもの" ], "comment": "knitting; knitted material; crochet" },
	{ "question": "編集", "answers": [ "へんしゅう" ], "comment": "editing; compilation; editorial (e.g. committee)" },
	{ "question": "緩い", "answers": [ "ゆるい" ], "comment": "lenient\nslow; stupid\nloose\nlenient; lax\ngentle (curve, slope, etc.)\nslow; weak\nsoft; not firm\ndifficult; hard" },
	{ "question": "緯度", "answers": [ "いど" ], "comment": "latitude (nav.)" },
	{ "question": "縛る", "answers": [ "しばる" ], "comment": "to tie; to bind" },
	{ "question": "縫う", "answers": [ "ぬう" ], "comment": "to sew; to stitch\nto weave one's way (e.g. through a crowd)" },
	{ "question": "縮む", "answers": [ "ちぢむ" ], "comment": "to shrink; to contract; to diminish (in size)" },
	{ "question": "縮める", "answers": [ "ちぢめる" ], "comment": "to shorten; to reduce; to condense; to shrink\nto crumple (fabric); to wrinkle\nto make (one's body) smaller; to draw in (one's legs); to duck (one's head)" },
	{ "question": "縮れる", "answers": [ "ちぢれる" ], "comment": "to be wavy; to be curled; to be frizzled" },
	{ "question": "縮小", "answers": [ "しゅくしょう" ], "comment": "reduction; curtailment" },
	{ "question": "缶詰", "answers": [ "かんづめ" ], "comment": "canned food; tinned food\nconfining someone (e.g. so they can concentrate on work)\nbeing stuck in a confined space" },
	{ "question": "羊毛", "answers": [ "ようもう" ], "comment": "wool" },
	{ "question": "美容", "answers": [ "びよう" ], "comment": "beauty of figure or form" },
	{ "question": "群れ", "answers": [ "むれ" ], "comment": "group; crowd; flock; herd; bevy; school; swarm; cluster (e.g. of stars); clump; pack (e.g. of dogs)" },
	{ "question": "羨ましい", "answers": [ "うらやましい" ], "comment": "envious (feeling, etc.); jealous\nenviable (position, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "羨む", "answers": [ "うらやむ" ], "comment": "to envy" },
	{ "question": "羽根", "answers": [ "はね" ], "comment": "feather; plume; down\nwing\nblade (of a fan, propeller, etc.)\nshuttlecock\narrow feathers" },
	{ "question": "習字", "answers": [ "しゅうじ" ], "comment": "penmanship" },
	{ "question": "耕す", "answers": [ "たがやす" ], "comment": "to till; to plow; to plough; to cultivate" },
	{ "question": "耕地", "answers": [ "こうち" ], "comment": "arable land" },
	{ "question": "職人", "answers": [ "しょくにん" ], "comment": "worker; mechanic; artisan; craftsman" },
	{ "question": "肌着", "answers": [ "はだぎ" ], "comment": "underwear; underclothes; lingerie; chemise; singlet" },
	{ "question": "肘", "answers": [ "ひじ" ], "comment": "elbow" },
	{ "question": "肯定", "answers": [ "こうてい" ], "comment": "positive; affirmation" },
	{ "question": "育児", "answers": [ "いくじ" ], "comment": "childcare; child-rearing; nursing; upbringing" },
	{ "question": "背負う", "answers": [ "せおう" ], "comment": "to carry on one's back\nto be burdened with; to take responsibility for\nto have (something) in the background; to be in front (of something)\nto be conceited; to think highly of oneself" },
	{ "question": "能率", "answers": [ "のうりつ" ], "comment": "efficiency\nmoment (i.e. magnetic moment)" },
	{ "question": "脂", "answers": [ "あぶら", "やに" ], "comment": "fat; tallow; lard; grease\nresin\n(tobacco) resin; tar; nicotine\nsleep (in one's eyes, i.e. eye mucus)" },
	{ "question": "脱線", "answers": [ "だっせん" ], "comment": "derailment\ndigression; deviation" },
	{ "question": "腰掛け", "answers": [ "こしかけ" ], "comment": "seat; bench" },
	{ "question": "腰掛ける", "answers": [ "こしかける" ], "comment": "to sit (down)" },
	{ "question": "膨らます", "answers": [ "ふくらます" ], "comment": "to swell; to expand; to inflate; to bulge" },
	{ "question": "膨らむ", "answers": [ "ふくらむ" ], "comment": "to expand; to swell (out); to get big; to become inflated" },
	{ "question": "膨大", "answers": [ "ぼうだい" ], "comment": "huge; vast; enormous; colossal; extensive; multitudinous\nswelling; expansion" },
	{ "question": "臨時", "answers": [ "りんじ" ], "comment": "temporary; special; extraordinary" },
	{ "question": "自治", "answers": [ "じち" ], "comment": "self-government; autonomy\nlocal (governmental) autonomy" },
	{ "question": "自然科学", "answers": [ "しぜんかがく" ], "comment": "natural science" },
	{ "question": "自習", "answers": [ "じしゅう" ], "comment": "self-study; teaching oneself" },
	{ "question": "自衛", "answers": [ "じえい" ], "comment": "self-defense; self-defence" },
	{ "question": "至急", "answers": [ "しきゅう" ], "comment": "urgent; pressing" },
	{ "question": "船便", "answers": [ "ふなびん" ], "comment": "surface mail (ship); sea mail\nferry service; steamer service" },
	{ "question": "艶", "answers": [ "つや", "えん", "あで" ], "comment": "gloss; glaze\ncharm; romance; love; youthfulness\ncolor; colour; feeling\ncharming; fascinating; voluptuous" },
	{ "question": "芯", "answers": [ "しん" ], "comment": "wick; marrow; staple (for stapler); (pencil) lead; stuffing; pith\ncore; heart; centre; center" },
	{ "question": "花嫁", "answers": [ "はなよめ" ], "comment": "bride" },
	{ "question": "花火", "answers": [ "はなび" ], "comment": "fireworks" },
	{ "question": "芸能", "answers": [ "げいのう" ], "comment": "public entertainment; performing arts\naccomplishments; attainments" },
	{ "question": "若々しい", "answers": [ "わかわかしい" ], "comment": "youthful; young" },
	{ "question": "苦心", "answers": [ "くしん" ], "comment": "pain; trouble; anxiety; diligence; hard work" },
	{ "question": "苦情", "answers": [ "くじょう" ], "comment": "complaint; troubles; objection; grievance" },
	{ "question": "英和", "answers": [ "えいわ" ], "comment": "English-Japanese (e.g. dictionary)" },
	{ "question": "英文", "answers": [ "えいぶん" ], "comment": "sentence in English; article in English; English text\nEnglish literature (study of)" },
	{ "question": "茂る", "answers": [ "しげる" ], "comment": "to grow thickly; to be in full leaf; to be rampant; to luxuriate; to be luxurious" },
	{ "question": "茶色い", "answers": [ "ちゃいろい" ], "comment": "light brown; tawny" },
	{ "question": "草履", "answers": [ "ぞうり" ], "comment": "zori; Japanese sandals" },
	{ "question": "荒い", "answers": [ "あらい" ], "comment": "rough; rude; wild" },
	{ "question": "落し物", "answers": [ "おとしもの" ], "comment": "lost property; something dropped and left behind" },
	{ "question": "落ち着く", "answers": [ "おちつく" ], "comment": "to calm down; to compose oneself; to regain presence of mind\nto calm down; to settle down; to die down; to become stable; to abate\nto settle down (in a location, job, etc.); to settle in\nto be settled; to be fixed; to have been reached\nto harmonize with; to harmonise with; to match; to suit; to fit\nto be unobtrusive; to be quiet; to be subdued" },
	{ "question": "落第", "answers": [ "らくだい" ], "comment": "failure; dropping out of a class" },
	{ "question": "著す", "answers": [ "あらわす" ], "comment": "to write; to publish" },
	{ "question": "葬式", "answers": [ "そうしき" ], "comment": "funeral" },
	{ "question": "蒸し暑い", "answers": [ "むしあつい" ], "comment": "humid; sultry" },
	{ "question": "蒸す", "answers": [ "むす" ], "comment": "to steam (food)\nto steam (food, towel, etc.)\nto be hot and humid; to be sultry" },
	{ "question": "蒸気", "answers": [ "じょうき" ], "comment": "steam; vapour; vapor\nsteamboat; steam locomotive" },
	{ "question": "蒸発", "answers": [ "じょうはつ" ], "comment": "evaporation\ndisappearance (of people intentionally concealing their whereabouts); unexplained disappearance" },
	{ "question": "蓄える", "answers": [ "たくわえる" ], "comment": "to store; to save up; to stock up on; to lay in stock; to set aside\nto accumulate (e.g. knowledge); to build up (e.g. experience); to develop (e.g. one's skills)\nto grow (a beard, moustache, etc.); to wear" },
	{ "question": "薄める", "answers": [ "うすめる" ], "comment": "to dilute; to water down" },
	{ "question": "薄暗い", "answers": [ "うすぐらい" ], "comment": "dim; gloomy" },
	{ "question": "薬品", "answers": [ "やくひん" ], "comment": "medicine; chemicals" },
	{ "question": "薬局", "answers": [ "やっきょく" ], "comment": "pharmacy; chemist (shop); drugstore" },
	{ "question": "薬指", "answers": [ "くすりゆび" ], "comment": "ring finger; fourth finger" },
	{ "question": "薬缶", "answers": [ "やかん" ], "comment": "kettle" },
	{ "question": "虹", "answers": [ "にじ" ], "comment": "rainbow" },
	{ "question": "蚊", "answers": [ "か" ], "comment": "mosquito" },
	{ "question": "蛇口", "answers": [ "じゃぐち" ], "comment": "faucet; tap" },
	{ "question": "蛍光灯", "answers": [ "けいこうとう" ], "comment": "fluorescent lamp; fluorescent light\nperson who is slow to react; someone slow on the uptake" },
	{ "question": "血圧", "answers": [ "けつあつ" ], "comment": "blood pressure" },
	{ "question": "血液", "answers": [ "けつえき" ], "comment": "blood" },
	{ "question": "行事", "answers": [ "ぎょうじ" ], "comment": "event; function" },
	{ "question": "行列", "answers": [ "ぎょうれつ" ], "comment": "line; queue; procession; parade\nmatrix" },
	{ "question": "街角", "answers": [ "まちかど" ], "comment": "street corner" },
	{ "question": "衣食住", "answers": [ "いしょくじゅう" ], "comment": "necessities of life (food, clothing & shelter)" },
	{ "question": "表紙", "answers": [ "ひょうし" ], "comment": "front cover; binding; (book) cover\nappearing on the cover of a magazine" },
	{ "question": "被せる", "answers": [ "かぶせる" ], "comment": "to cover (with something); to put on (e.g. on someone else's head); to plate something (with a metal); to pour or dash a liquid (on something); to charge (a person with a guilt)" },
	{ "question": "裁縫", "answers": [ "さいほう" ], "comment": "sewing" },
	{ "question": "裂く", "answers": [ "さく" ], "comment": "to tear; to rip up\nto cut up; to cleave; to cut open (esp. the abdomen)\nto forcibly separate (e.g. two lovers)\nto have a tattoo in the corner of one's eye" },
	{ "question": "裏口", "answers": [ "うらぐち" ], "comment": "backdoor; rear entrance" },
	{ "question": "裏返す", "answers": [ "うらがえす" ], "comment": "to turn inside out; to turn the other way; to turn (something) over" },
	{ "question": "補う", "answers": [ "おぎなう" ], "comment": "to compensate for; to supplement" },
	{ "question": "製作", "answers": [ "せいさく" ], "comment": "manufacture; production" },
	{ "question": "複写", "answers": [ "ふくしゃ" ], "comment": "copy; duplicate" },
	{ "question": "複数", "answers": [ "ふくすう" ], "comment": "several; plural; plurality; multiple" },
	{ "question": "西暦", "answers": [ "せいれき" ], "comment": "Christian Era; CE; anno domini; AD\nWestern (Gregorian) calendar" },
	{ "question": "要旨", "answers": [ "ようし" ], "comment": "point; essentials; gist; summary; fundamentals" },
	{ "question": "要領", "answers": [ "ようりょう" ], "comment": "point; gist; essentials; tenets; outline\nknack; trick; the ropes" },
	{ "question": "見下ろす", "answers": [ "みおろす" ], "comment": "to overlook; to command a view of; to look down on\nto despise; to look down on" },
	{ "question": "見付かる", "answers": [ "みつかる" ], "comment": "to be found; to be discovered" },
	{ "question": "見付ける", "answers": [ "みつける" ], "comment": "to discover; to find (e.g. an error in a book); to come across; to detect; to spot\nto locate; to find (e.g. something missing); to find fault\nto be used to seeing; to be familiar with" },
	{ "question": "見出し", "answers": [ "みだし" ], "comment": "heading; headline; title; caption\nindex\nheadword" },
	{ "question": "見学", "answers": [ "けんがく" ], "comment": "inspection; study by observation; field trip" },
	{ "question": "見慣れる", "answers": [ "みなれる" ], "comment": "to become used to seeing; to be familiar with" },
	{ "question": "見掛け", "answers": [ "みかけ" ], "comment": "outward appearance\napparent" },
	{ "question": "見本", "answers": [ "みほん" ], "comment": "sample; specimen; pattern\nmodel; example" },
	{ "question": "見直す", "answers": [ "みなおす" ], "comment": "to look again\nto re-examine (policy, estimate, plan, etc.); to review\nto get a better opinion of; to see something in a more positive light\nto improve; to recover (market, illness, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "見舞う", "answers": [ "みまう" ], "comment": "to ask after (someone's health); to visit\nto attack; to strike; to meet with misfortune; to suffer an attack" },
	{ "question": "見送る", "answers": [ "みおくる" ], "comment": "to see someone off (at a station, an airport, etc.); to escort (e.g. home)\nto follow something with one's eyes until it is out of sight\nto let pass; to pass up (an opportunity etc.); to let a pitch go by (baseball); to watch a batted ball go into the stands\nto shelve (a plan, deliberation on a bill, etc.); to postpone\nto have someone related or close to you die; to bury someone\nto take care of somebody until he dies\nto wait and see; to continue (e.g. in legal contexts)" },
	{ "question": "規律", "answers": [ "きりつ" ], "comment": "order; observance; discipline\nrules; law; regulations" },
	{ "question": "規準", "answers": [ "きじゅん" ], "comment": "standard; basis; criterion; norm; reference; datum" },
	{ "question": "親指", "answers": [ "おやゆび" ], "comment": "thumb" },
	{ "question": "親類", "answers": [ "しんるい" ], "comment": "relation; kin" },
	{ "question": "観念", "answers": [ "かんねん" ], "comment": "idea; notion; conception\nsense (e.g. of duty)\nresignation; preparedness; acceptance\nobservation and contemplation" },
	{ "question": "観測", "answers": [ "かんそく" ], "comment": "observation; survey; measurement" },
	{ "question": "角度", "answers": [ "かくど" ], "comment": "angle" },
	{ "question": "解放", "answers": [ "かいほう" ], "comment": "release; unleashing; liberation; emancipation; setting free\ndeallocation (of computer memory)" },
	{ "question": "解散", "answers": [ "かいさん" ], "comment": "breakup; dissolution" },
	{ "question": "解答", "answers": [ "かいとう" ], "comment": "answer; solution" },
	{ "question": "解説", "answers": [ "かいせつ" ], "comment": "explanation; commentary; exposition; elucidation" },
	{ "question": "言い付ける", "answers": [ "いいつける" ], "comment": "to tell (to do); to order; to charge; to direct\nto tell on (someone); to report\nto often say" },
	{ "question": "言い出す", "answers": [ "いいだす" ], "comment": "to start talking; to speak; to tell; to propose; to suggest; to break the ice" },
	{ "question": "言付ける", "answers": [ "ことづける" ], "comment": "to tell (to do); to order; to charge; to direct\nto tell on (someone); to report\nto often say\nto send word; to send a message\nto make an excuse; to make a pretext of" },
	{ "question": "言葉遣い", "answers": [ "ことばづかい" ], "comment": "speech; expression; wording; language" },
	{ "question": "討つ", "answers": [ "うつ" ], "comment": "to shoot (at)\nto attack; to defeat; to destroy; to avenge" },
	{ "question": "記号", "answers": [ "きごう" ], "comment": "symbol; code; sign; notation" },
	{ "question": "訳す", "answers": [ "やくす" ], "comment": "to translate; to interpret" },
	{ "question": "診る", "answers": [ "みる" ], "comment": "to examine (medically)" },
	{ "question": "診断", "answers": [ "しんだん" ], "comment": "diagnosis; medical examination" },
	{ "question": "評論", "answers": [ "ひょうろん" ], "comment": "criticism; critique" },
	{ "question": "詰まる", "answers": [ "つまる" ], "comment": "to be packed (with); to be full (space, schedule, etc.)\nto be blocked (road, pipe, etc.); to be clogged; to be plugged up\nto shorten (width, interval, etc.); to shrink (shirt, word form, etc.); to narrow\nto be at a loss; to be hard pressed\nto end up; to be settled\nto become a geminate consonant\nto hit the ball near the handle of the bat" },
	{ "question": "話し掛ける", "answers": [ "はなしかける" ], "comment": "to address (someone); to accost a person; to talk (to someone)\nto begin to talk; to start a conversation" },
	{ "question": "話中", "answers": [ "はなしちゅう" ], "comment": "busy (phone)" },
	{ "question": "話合い", "answers": [ "はなしあい" ], "comment": "discussion; conference" },
	{ "question": "誓う", "answers": [ "ちかう" ], "comment": "to swear; to vow; to take an oath; to pledge" },
	{ "question": "課程", "answers": [ "かてい" ], "comment": "course; curriculum" },
	{ "question": "課税", "answers": [ "かぜい" ], "comment": "taxation" },
	{ "question": "調味料", "answers": [ "ちょうみりょう" ], "comment": "flavoring (e.g. salt, sugar, soy sauce, vinegar, etc.); seasoning" },
	{ "question": "調整", "answers": [ "ちょうせい" ], "comment": "adjustment; regulation; coordination; reconciliation; tuning; fixing; tailoring" },
	{ "question": "調節", "answers": [ "ちょうせつ" ], "comment": "regulation; adjustment; control" },
	{ "question": "請う", "answers": [ "こう" ], "comment": "to beg; to ask; to request; to invite" },
	{ "question": "論ずる", "answers": [ "ろんずる" ], "comment": "to discuss; to talk about; to deal with (a topic)\nto argue; to dispute\nto take into consideration; to make an issue of" },
	{ "question": "謎謎", "answers": [ "なぞなぞ" ], "comment": "riddle; puzzle; enigma" },
	{ "question": "謙虚", "answers": [ "けんきょ" ], "comment": "modesty; humility" },
	{ "question": "謙遜", "answers": [ "けんそん" ], "comment": "modesty; humility; being humble" },
	{ "question": "講師", "answers": [ "こうし" ], "comment": "lecturer" },
	{ "question": "警備", "answers": [ "けいび" ], "comment": "defense; defence; guard; policing; security" },
	{ "question": "貝", "answers": [ "かい", "ばい" ], "comment": "shellfish\nseashell; shell\nJapanese babylon (species of shelled mollusk, Babylonia japonica); Japanese ivory shell\nspinning top (traditionally made from a Japanese babylon shell)" },
	{ "question": "貨物", "answers": [ "かもつ" ], "comment": "cargo; freight\nmoney or assets" },
	{ "question": "貯蔵", "answers": [ "ちょぞう" ], "comment": "storage; preservation" },
	{ "question": "貸し出し", "answers": [ "かしだし" ], "comment": "lending; loaning" },
	{ "question": "貸家", "answers": [ "かしや" ], "comment": "house for rent" },
	{ "question": "貸間", "answers": [ "かしま" ], "comment": "room to let; room for rent" },
	{ "question": "貼る", "answers": [ "はる" ], "comment": "to stick; to paste; to affix\nto stretch; to spread; to strain; to tighten; to put up (tent)\nto form (e.g. ice on a pond)\nto fill; to swell\nto stick out; to put; to slap\nto be expensive\nto keep a watch on; to be on the lookout\nto span; to generate" },
	{ "question": "資料", "answers": [ "しりょう" ], "comment": "materials; data; document" },
	{ "question": "賞品", "answers": [ "しょうひん" ], "comment": "prize; trophy" },
	{ "question": "賞金", "answers": [ "しょうきん" ], "comment": "prize; monetary award" },
	{ "question": "赤道", "answers": [ "せきどう" ], "comment": "equator" },
	{ "question": "起床", "answers": [ "きしょう" ], "comment": "rising; getting out of bed" },
	{ "question": "超える", "answers": [ "こえる" ], "comment": "to cross over; to cross; to pass through; to pass over (out of)\nto exceed" },
	{ "question": "超す", "answers": [ "こす" ], "comment": "to cross over (e.g. mountain); to go across\nto go over (e.g. with audience)\nto pass time (e.g. a winter)\nto surpass; to be better than; to exceed\nto move house\nto go; to come" },
	{ "question": "超過", "answers": [ "ちょうか" ], "comment": "excess; being more than" },
	{ "question": "足る", "answers": [ "たる" ], "comment": "to be sufficient; to be enough; to be worthy of" },
	{ "question": "足袋", "answers": [ "たび" ], "comment": "tabi; Japanese socks (with split toe)" },
	{ "question": "足跡", "answers": [ "あしあと" ], "comment": "footprints\nrecord of page visitors (e.g. in social networking sites)" },
	{ "question": "跳ねる", "answers": [ "はねる" ], "comment": "to jump; to leap; to prance; to spring up; to bound; to hop\nto break up; to close; to come to an end\nto hit (e.g. to have a car hit something or someone)" },
	{ "question": "跳ぶ", "answers": [ "とぶ" ], "comment": "to fly; to soar\nto jump; to leap; to spring; to bound; to hop" },
	{ "question": "踏切", "answers": [ "ふみきり" ], "comment": "railway crossing; railroad crossing; train crossing; level crossing\nstarting line; scratch\ndetermination\nstepping over the edge of the ring" },
	{ "question": "蹴る", "answers": [ "ける" ], "comment": "to kick\nto refuse; to reject" },
	{ "question": "身分", "answers": [ "みぶん" ], "comment": "social position; social status" },
	{ "question": "車庫", "answers": [ "しゃこ" ], "comment": "garage; carport; depot (trains, buses, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "車掌", "answers": [ "しゃしょう" ], "comment": "(train) conductor" },
	{ "question": "車輪", "answers": [ "しゃりん" ], "comment": "(car) wheel" },
	{ "question": "軟らかい", "answers": [ "やわらかい" ], "comment": "soft; tender; limp; limber\ngentle; mild\ninformal; lighter" },
	{ "question": "転々", "answers": [ "てんてん" ], "comment": "moving from place to place; being passed around repeatedly\nrolling about" },
	{ "question": "転がす", "answers": [ "ころがす" ], "comment": "to roll\nto turn over; to tip over; to throw down\nto leave\nto buy and sell (quickly for a profit)" },
	{ "question": "転がる", "answers": [ "ころがる" ], "comment": "to roll; to tumble\nto fall over; to roll over\nto lie down\nto be scattered about; to be common\n(of a situation or outcome) to change; to turn out" },
	{ "question": "載せる", "answers": [ "のせる" ], "comment": "to place on (something)\nto give (someone) a ride; to give a lift; to pick up; to help on board\nto load (luggage); to carry; to take on board\nto send out (on the airwaves, etc.)\nto deceive; to take for a ride\nto (sing) along with (musical accompaniment)\nto let (someone) take part\nto excite (someone)\nto publish (an article); to run (an ad)" },
	{ "question": "載る", "answers": [ "のる" ], "comment": "to be placed on; to be set on; to be piled on; to be loaded on\nto appear (in print); to be mentioned; to be recorded; to be reported; to be given" },
	{ "question": "輸血", "answers": [ "ゆけつ" ], "comment": "blood transfusion" },
	{ "question": "輸送", "answers": [ "ゆそう" ], "comment": "transport; transportation" },
	{ "question": "農村", "answers": [ "のうそん" ], "comment": "agricultural community; farm village\nrural" },
	{ "question": "農産物", "answers": [ "のうさんぶつ" ], "comment": "agricultural produce" },
	{ "question": "農薬", "answers": [ "のうやく" ], "comment": "agricultural chemical (i.e. pesticide, herbicide, fungicide, etc.); agrochemical; agrichemical" },
	{ "question": "近々", "answers": [ "ちかぢか" ], "comment": "soon; nearness; before long" },
	{ "question": "近付ける", "answers": [ "ちかづける" ], "comment": "to bring near; to put close; to let come near; to associate with" },
	{ "question": "近寄る", "answers": [ "ちかよる" ], "comment": "to approach; to draw near" },
	{ "question": "迫る", "answers": [ "せまる" ], "comment": "to approach; to draw near; to be imminent\nto press (someone for something); to urge; to compel" },
	{ "question": "述語", "answers": [ "じゅつご" ], "comment": "predicate" },
	{ "question": "迷信", "answers": [ "めいしん" ], "comment": "superstition; superstitious belief" },
	{ "question": "追い掛ける", "answers": [ "おいかける" ], "comment": "to chase; to run after; to pursue" },
	{ "question": "追い越す", "answers": [ "おいこす" ], "comment": "to pass (e.g. car); to overtake\nto surpass; to outstrip; to get ahead of; to outdistance" },
	{ "question": "追加", "answers": [ "ついか" ], "comment": "addition; supplement; append (e.g. to a file); appendix" },
	{ "question": "送り仮名", "answers": [ "おくりがな" ], "comment": "kana written after a kanji to complete the full (usually kun) reading of the word (may inflect); declensional kana ending" },
	{ "question": "送別", "answers": [ "そうべつ" ], "comment": "farewell; send-off" },
	{ "question": "送料", "answers": [ "そうりょう" ], "comment": "postage; carriage; shipping charge" },
	{ "question": "逃がす", "answers": [ "にがす" ], "comment": "to set free; to let go; to release\nto miss (e.g. a chance); to lose; to let get away; to fail to catch" },
	{ "question": "逆さ", "answers": [ "さかさ" ], "comment": "reverse; inversion; upside down" },
	{ "question": "逆様", "answers": [ "さかさま" ], "comment": "inverted; upside down" },
	{ "question": "透き通る", "answers": [ "すきとおる" ], "comment": "to be transparent; to be see-through\nto be clear (voice)" },
	{ "question": "透明", "answers": [ "とうめい" ], "comment": "transparent; clear" },
	{ "question": "通ずる", "answers": [ "つうずる" ], "comment": "to be open (to traffic); to lead to; to communicate (with)\nto flow (liquid, current); to pass; to get through to\nto be understood; to be comprehended\nto be honored; to be good\nto be well versed in; to be well-informed\nto communicate clandestinely; to keep in touch (e.g. with the enemy)\nto form a liaison; to be intimate" },
	{ "question": "通り掛かる", "answers": [ "とおりかかる" ], "comment": "to happen to pass by" },
	{ "question": "通勤", "answers": [ "つうきん" ], "comment": "commuting to work" },
	{ "question": "通帳", "answers": [ "つうちょう" ], "comment": "passbook; bankbook" },
	{ "question": "通用", "answers": [ "つうよう" ], "comment": "popular use; circulation\nto pass as; to pass for" },
	{ "question": "通知", "answers": [ "つうち" ], "comment": "notice; notification; report; posting" },
	{ "question": "通訳", "answers": [ "つうやく" ], "comment": "interpretation (i.e. oral translation); interpreter" },
	{ "question": "通貨", "answers": [ "つうか" ], "comment": "currency" },
	{ "question": "通路", "answers": [ "つうろ" ], "comment": "passage; pathway; roadway; avenue; aisle" },
	{ "question": "速力", "answers": [ "そくりょく" ], "comment": "speed" },
	{ "question": "速達", "answers": [ "そくたつ" ], "comment": "express; special delivery" },
	{ "question": "造る", "answers": [ "つくる" ], "comment": "to make; to produce; to manufacture; to build; to construct\nto prepare (food); to brew (alcohol)\nto raise; to grow; to cultivate; to train\nto till\nto draw up (a document); to make out; to prepare; to write\nto create (an artistic work, etc.); to compose\nto coin (a phrase); to organize; to organise; to establish; to found\nto have (a child)\nto make up (one's face, etc.)\nto fabricate (an excuse, etc.)\nto form (a line, etc.)\nto set (a record)\nto commit (a sin, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "造船", "answers": [ "ぞうせん" ], "comment": "shipbuilding" },
	{ "question": "連合", "answers": [ "れんごう" ], "comment": "union; alliance; combination\nRENGO (Japanese Trade Union Confederation)" },
	{ "question": "逸れる", "answers": [ "それる" ], "comment": "to turn away; to bear off; to veer away; to swerve from; to miss (e.g. a target)\nto deviate (e.g. of a conversation); to digress; to to go astray; to wander\nto lose sight of (one's companions); to stray from\nto miss (one's chance to ...)" },
	{ "question": "遊園地", "answers": [ "ゆうえんち" ], "comment": "amusement park" },
	{ "question": "運河", "answers": [ "うんが" ], "comment": "canal; waterway" },
	{ "question": "過剰", "answers": [ "かじょう" ], "comment": "excess; surplus; over-" },
	{ "question": "過半数", "answers": [ "かはんすう" ], "comment": "majority" },
	{ "question": "過失", "answers": [ "かしつ" ], "comment": "error; blunder; accident\nfault; defect" },
	{ "question": "過程", "answers": [ "かてい" ], "comment": "process; course; mechanism" },
	{ "question": "道順", "answers": [ "みちじゅん" ], "comment": "itinerary; route" },
	{ "question": "遠足", "answers": [ "えんそく" ], "comment": "excursion; outing; trip" },
	{ "question": "遡る", "answers": [ "さかのぼる" ], "comment": "to go upstream\nto go back (in time, to origin); to date back to; to trace back to; to make retroactive" },
	{ "question": "適確", "answers": [ "てきかく" ], "comment": "precise; accurate; appropriate; exactly the right" },
	{ "question": "遭う", "answers": [ "あう" ], "comment": "to meet; to encounter; to see\nto have an accident; to have a bad experience" },
	{ "question": "郡", "answers": [ "ぐん", "こおり" ], "comment": "district; county\ndistrict (of 2-20 50-home neighbourhoods or townships, in the ritsuryo period)" },
	{ "question": "部品", "answers": [ "ぶひん" ], "comment": "parts; accessories; components" },
	{ "question": "部首", "answers": [ "ぶしゅ" ], "comment": "radical (of a kanji character)" },
	{ "question": "郵送", "answers": [ "ゆうそう" ], "comment": "mailing" },
	{ "question": "都心", "answers": [ "としん" ], "comment": "city centre (center) (esp. capital city); urban centre; heart of city a metropolis" },
	{ "question": "酌む", "answers": [ "くむ" ], "comment": "to serve sake" },
	{ "question": "配る", "answers": [ "くばる" ], "comment": "to distribute; to deliver; to deal (cards)" },
	{ "question": "酒場", "answers": [ "さかば" ], "comment": "bar; pub; tavern" },
	{ "question": "酔っ払い", "answers": [ "よっぱらい" ], "comment": "drunkard" },
	{ "question": "酢", "answers": [ "す" ], "comment": "vinegar" },
	{ "question": "酸性", "answers": [ "さんせい" ], "comment": "acidity\nacidic" },
	{ "question": "醜い", "answers": [ "みにくい" ], "comment": "ugly; unattractive\nunsightly; unseemly" },
	{ "question": "重たい", "answers": [ "おもたい" ], "comment": "heavy; massive; serious; important; severe; oppressed" },
	{ "question": "重なる", "answers": [ "かさなる" ], "comment": "to be piled up; to lie on top of one another\nto come one after another; to happen over and over; to pile up (e.g. stress); to accumulate\nto overlap (each other); to occur at the same time; to happen simultaneously\nmain; principal; important" },
	{ "question": "重ねる", "answers": [ "かさねる" ], "comment": "to pile up; to put something on top of another; to stack up\nto repeat many times over; to go through something repeatedly" },
	{ "question": "重体", "answers": [ "じゅうたい" ], "comment": "seriously ill; serious condition; critical state" },
	{ "question": "重力", "answers": [ "じゅうりょく" ], "comment": "gravity; gravitation; gravitational pull" },
	{ "question": "重役", "answers": [ "じゅうやく" ], "comment": "company director; top management; high executive; (person with) heavy responsibilities" },
	{ "question": "重点", "answers": [ "じゅうてん" ], "comment": "important point; emphasis; stress; importance; priority\niteration mark\ncolon (punctuation)" },
	{ "question": "重量", "answers": [ "じゅうりょう" ], "comment": "weight\nheavyweight boxer" },
	{ "question": "量る", "answers": [ "はかる" ], "comment": "to measure; to weigh; to survey; to time (sound, gauge, estimate)\nto conjecture; to infer; to surmise" },
	{ "question": "金魚", "answers": [ "きんぎょ" ], "comment": "goldfish" },
	{ "question": "釜", "answers": [ "かま" ], "comment": "iron pot; kettle" },
	{ "question": "針路", "answers": [ "しんろ" ], "comment": "course; direction" },
	{ "question": "針金", "answers": [ "はりがね" ], "comment": "wire" },
	{ "question": "釣り合う", "answers": [ "つりあう" ], "comment": "to balance; to be in harmony; to be in equilibrium\nto suit; to go well together; to be a good match" },
	{ "question": "釣る", "answers": [ "つる" ], "comment": "to fish; to angle; to catch\nto lure in; to tempt; to attract; to entice; to allure" },
	{ "question": "鈍い", "answers": [ "にぶい" ], "comment": "slow\nlate (e.g. \"late at night\")\ntoo late\ndull; stupid\ndull (e.g. a knife); blunt\nthickheaded; obtuse; stupid\ndull (sound, color, etc.); dim (light)\nslow; sluggish; inert; lethargic\nindulgent (esp. to the opposite sex); doting" },
	{ "question": "鈴", "answers": [ "すず", "りん" ], "comment": "bell (often globular)" },
	{ "question": "鉄橋", "answers": [ "てっきょう" ], "comment": "railway bridge; iron bridge" },
	{ "question": "鉄砲", "answers": [ "てっぽう" ], "comment": "gun\nwooden pole that wrestlers strike in practice\nfugu" },
	{ "question": "鉢", "answers": [ "はち" ], "comment": "bowl; pot; basin\nflowerpot\ncrown; brainpan" },
	{ "question": "鉱物", "answers": [ "こうぶつ" ], "comment": "mineral" },
	{ "question": "銅", "answers": [ "どう", "あかがね" ], "comment": "money\nmetal\ncopper (Cu)\nbronze (medal)" },
	{ "question": "銘々", "answers": [ "めいめい" ], "comment": "each; individual" },
	{ "question": "録音", "answers": [ "ろくおん" ], "comment": "(audio) recording" },
	{ "question": "鏡", "answers": [ "かがみ" ], "comment": "mirror; looking-glass\nbarrel head" },
	{ "question": "鐘", "answers": [ "かね" ], "comment": "bell (often a large hanging bell); chime" },
	{ "question": "鑑賞", "answers": [ "かんしょう" ], "comment": "appreciation (e.g. of art); aesthetic sense" },
	{ "question": "長女", "answers": [ "ちょうじょ" ], "comment": "eldest daughter; first-born daughter" },
	{ "question": "長引く", "answers": [ "ながびく" ], "comment": "to be prolonged; to drag on" },
	{ "question": "長所", "answers": [ "ちょうしょ" ], "comment": "strong point; merit; virtue; advantage" },
	{ "question": "長方形", "answers": [ "ちょうほうけい" ], "comment": "rectangle; oblong" },
	{ "question": "長男", "answers": [ "ちょうなん" ], "comment": "eldest son (may be the only son); first-born son" },
	{ "question": "長短", "answers": [ "ちょうたん" ], "comment": "length\nlong and short; advantages and disadvantages; pluses and minuses; strong and weak points; merits and demerits" },
	{ "question": "閉会", "answers": [ "へいかい" ], "comment": "closure (of a ceremony, event, meeting, etc.)" },
	{ "question": "開会", "answers": [ "かいかい" ], "comment": "opening of a meeting" },
	{ "question": "開放", "answers": [ "かいほう" ], "comment": "open; throw open; liberalization; liberalisation" },
	{ "question": "開通", "answers": [ "かいつう" ], "comment": "opening; open; taking effect; becoming active" },
	{ "question": "間も無く", "answers": [ "まもなく" ], "comment": "soon; before long; in a short time\nlacking time to ...; without time to ..." },
	{ "question": "間接", "answers": [ "かんせつ" ], "comment": "indirection; indirectness" },
	{ "question": "間隔", "answers": [ "かんかく" ], "comment": "space; interval; SPC" },
	{ "question": "関東", "answers": [ "かんとう" ], "comment": "Kanto; region consisting of Tokyo and surrounding prefectures\nKanto; north-eastern half of Japan (during the feudal era)" },
	{ "question": "関西", "answers": [ "かんさい" ], "comment": "Kansai; region consisting of Osaka, Kobe, Kyoto and surrounding prefectures\nKansai; south-western half of Japan (during the feudal era)" },
	{ "question": "防止", "answers": [ "ぼうし" ], "comment": "prevention; check" },
	{ "question": "防犯", "answers": [ "ぼうはん" ], "comment": "prevention of crime" },
	{ "question": "附属", "answers": [ "ふぞく" ], "comment": "attached; belonging (to); included; enclosed; affiliated; annexed; associated; subordinate; incidental; dependent; auxiliary" },
	{ "question": "限度", "answers": [ "げんど" ], "comment": "limit; bounds" },
	{ "question": "険しい", "answers": [ "けわしい" ], "comment": "precipitous; rugged; inaccessible; impregnable; steep\ngrim; severe; stern" },
	{ "question": "随筆", "answers": [ "ずいひつ" ], "comment": "essays; miscellaneous writings; literary jottings" },
	{ "question": "隔てる", "answers": [ "へだてる" ], "comment": "to separate (by distance, time, etc.); to isolate; to partition; to divide\nto interpose; to have between\nto alienate; to estrange" },
	{ "question": "隙間", "answers": [ "すきま" ], "comment": "crevice; crack; gap; opening; clearance\nspare moment; interval; break; pause; spare time\nchink (in one's armor, armour); unpreparedness; carelessness" },
	{ "question": "障子", "answers": [ "しょうじ" ], "comment": "shoji (paper sliding door)" },
	{ "question": "隣", "answers": [ "となり" ], "comment": "neighbor (neighbour); next to (esp. living next door to)" },
	{ "question": "集会", "answers": [ "しゅうかい" ], "comment": "meeting; assembly; gathering; congregation; convention; rally" },
	{ "question": "集合", "answers": [ "しゅうごう" ], "comment": "gathering; assembly; meeting\nset" },
	{ "question": "集金", "answers": [ "しゅうきん" ], "comment": "money collection" },
	{ "question": "雑巾", "answers": [ "ぞうきん" ], "comment": "house-cloth; dust cloth" },
	{ "question": "雑音", "answers": [ "ざつおん" ], "comment": "noise (usu. unpleasant)\ninterference (e.g. radio); static; noise\ngossip; irresponsible criticism" },
	{ "question": "雨戸", "answers": [ "あまど" ], "comment": "sliding storm shutter" },
	{ "question": "零点", "answers": [ "れいてん" ], "comment": "zero; no marks\nzero; root" },
	{ "question": "電力", "answers": [ "でんりょく" ], "comment": "electric power" },
	{ "question": "電柱", "answers": [ "でんちゅう" ], "comment": "utility pole; power pole; telephone pole; telegraph pole; lightpole" },
	{ "question": "電池", "answers": [ "でんち" ], "comment": "battery; cell" },
	{ "question": "電波", "answers": [ "でんぱ" ], "comment": "electromagnetic wave; radio wave; reception; signal\nsaying strange things" },
	{ "question": "電流", "answers": [ "でんりゅう" ], "comment": "electric current" },
	{ "question": "電球", "answers": [ "でんきゅう" ], "comment": "light bulb" },
	{ "question": "青少年", "answers": [ "せいしょうねん" ], "comment": "youth; young person" },
	{ "question": "青白い", "answers": [ "あおじろい" ], "comment": "pale; pallid\nbluish-white" },
	{ "question": "静まる", "answers": [ "しずまる" ], "comment": "to quieten down; to calm down; to subside; to die down; to abate; to be suppressed" },
	{ "question": "面倒臭い", "answers": [ "めんどうくさい" ], "comment": "bothersome; tiresome; bother to do" },
	{ "question": "面接", "answers": [ "めんせつ" ], "comment": "interview (e.g. for a job)" },
	{ "question": "面積", "answers": [ "めんせき" ], "comment": "square measure; size (e.g. of land); area; surface" },
	{ "question": "靴", "answers": [ "くつ" ], "comment": "shoes; boots; footwear; footgear" },
	{ "question": "靴下", "answers": [ "くつした" ], "comment": "socks; sock; stockings; stocking" },
	{ "question": "響き", "answers": [ "ひびき" ], "comment": "commotion; stir\necho; reverberation\nsound (esp. the distinctive sound of an object or activity, e.g. rain, gun, gallop, drum); noise\nquality of a sound (e.g. a fine phrase, clear voice, resonant bell); feeling of a sound; emotion or feeling inspired by something heard or read" },
	{ "question": "響く", "answers": [ "ひびく" ], "comment": "to resound; to be heard far away\nto reverberate; to shake; to vibrate\nto come (home); to remain (with someone)\nto have an effect; to make an impression\nto resound\nto make a stir" },
	{ "question": "頂点", "answers": [ "ちょうてん" ], "comment": "top; summit\nvertex" },
	{ "question": "項目", "answers": [ "こうもく" ], "comment": "(data) item; entry" },
	{ "question": "順々", "answers": [ "じゅんじゅん" ], "comment": "in order; in turn" },
	{ "question": "順序", "answers": [ "じゅんじょ" ], "comment": "order; sequence; procedure" },
	{ "question": "預かる", "answers": [ "あずかる" ], "comment": "to look after; to take care of; to keep; to hold on to; to keep in custody\nto take charge of; to be entrusted with; to receive on deposit\nto reserve (judgment); to leave undecided" },
	{ "question": "領事", "answers": [ "りょうじ" ], "comment": "consul" },
	{ "question": "領収", "answers": [ "りょうしゅう" ], "comment": "receipt; voucher\nto receive" },
	{ "question": "頭脳", "answers": [ "ずのう" ], "comment": "head; brains\nintellect; understanding" },
	{ "question": "頼もしい", "answers": [ "たのもしい" ], "comment": "reliable; trustworthy\nhopeful; promising" },
	{ "question": "題名", "answers": [ "だいめい" ], "comment": "title" },
	{ "question": "顕微鏡", "answers": [ "けんびきょう" ], "comment": "microscope" },
	{ "question": "風呂敷", "answers": [ "ふろしき" ], "comment": "wrapping cloth; cloth wrapper" },
	{ "question": "風船", "answers": [ "ふうせん" ], "comment": "balloon (esp. small, toy variety)" },
	{ "question": "風邪", "answers": [ "かぜ" ], "comment": "common cold; cold; influenza; flu; ague" },
	{ "question": "飛び込む", "answers": [ "とびこむ" ], "comment": "to jump in; to leap in; to plunge into; to dive\nto burst in; to barge in" },
	{ "question": "食器", "answers": [ "しょっき" ], "comment": "tableware" },
	{ "question": "食塩", "answers": [ "しょくえん" ], "comment": "table salt" },
	{ "question": "飢える", "answers": [ "うえる" ], "comment": "to starve; to thirst; to be hungry" },
	{ "question": "飼う", "answers": [ "かう" ], "comment": "to keep (a pet or other animal); to raise; to have; to own; to feed" },
	{ "question": "飽くまで", "answers": [ "あくまで" ], "comment": "to the end; to the bitter end; to the last; stubbornly; persistently; consistently; to the utmost\nafter all; it must be remembered; only; purely; simply" },
	{ "question": "飾り", "answers": [ "かざり" ], "comment": "decoration" },
	{ "question": "餅", "answers": [ "もち" ], "comment": "sticky rice cake\nmochi rice cake" },
	{ "question": "養分", "answers": [ "ようぶん" ], "comment": "nourishment; nutrient" },
	{ "question": "香水", "answers": [ "こうすい" ], "comment": "perfume\nscented water used for purification; water offering to Buddha" },
	{ "question": "騒々しい", "answers": [ "そうぞうしい" ], "comment": "noisy; boisterous" },
	{ "question": "騒がしい", "answers": [ "さわがしい" ], "comment": "noisy; boisterous\nturbulent (era, etc.); troubled" },
	{ "question": "高める", "answers": [ "たかめる" ], "comment": "to raise; to lift; to boost; to enhance" },
	{ "question": "高層", "answers": [ "こうそう" ], "comment": "multistory; multistoried; high-rise; high; tall" },
	{ "question": "高度", "answers": [ "こうど" ], "comment": "altitude; height; elevation\nadvanced; sophisticated; high-grade; strong" },
	{ "question": "高等", "answers": [ "こうとう" ], "comment": "high class; high grade" },
	{ "question": "高級", "answers": [ "こうきゅう" ], "comment": "high class; high grade\nhigh rank; seniority" },
	{ "question": "鳴らす", "answers": [ "ならす" ], "comment": "to ring; to sound; to chime; to beat; to snort (nose); to snap (fingers)\nto be popular; to be esteemed; to be reputed\nto state; to insist; to complain\nto fart (loudly)" }
]
}
